<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>1777</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Systematic versus opportunistic risk assessment for the primary prevention of cardiovascular disease: Cochrane systematic review protocol</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Dyakova, Mariana</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Drew, Christian</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Wright, Nicola</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Clarke, Aileen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Rees, Karen</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">cardiovascular disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Cochrane systematic review protocol</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">risk assessment</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">A large number of people, considered at increased risk of vascular disease, remainunidentified, untreated and not reached by lifestyle advice or intervention, despite publichealth and clinical efforts. This has prompted the initiation of national  screening/systematic risk assessment programmes for vascular disease in healthy populations. These exist in addition to the more ad hoc opportunistic risk assessment initiatives undertaken worldwide. There is currently not enough indisputable evidence either showing clear clinical or economic benefits of systematic screening-like programmes over opportunistic risk assessment of cardiovascular disease (CVD) in primary care. We present the rationale and methodology of a Cochrane systematic review, assessing the effectiveness, costs and adverse effects of systematic risk assessment compared to opportunistic risk assessment for the primary prevention of CVD.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlagublishing House</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1777</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/seejph-1777</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume I, 2014</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume I, 2014</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1777/1698</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 Mariana Dyakova, Christian Drew, Nicola Wright, Aileen Clarke, Karen Rees</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>