<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>1785</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Self-perceived level of competencies of family physicians in transitional Kosovo</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Skeraj, Fitim</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Czabanowska, Katarzyna</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Bojaj, Gazmend</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Burazeri, Genc</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">competencies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">family physicians</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">general practitioners</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">primary health care</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Aim: Family physicians and general practitioners are currently facing increasing demands to meet patients’ expectations and rapid technological and scientific developments. The aim of this study was to determine the self-perceived level of competencies of primary health care physicians in Kosovo, a post-war country in the Western Balkans.Methods: A cross-sectional study was conducted in Kosovo in 2013 including arepresentative sample of 597 primary health care physicians (295 men and 302 women; mean age: 46.0±9.4 years; response rate: 90%). A structured self-administered questionnaire was used in order to determine physicians’ competencies regarding different domains of the quality of health care. The questionnaire included 37 items organized into six subscales/domains. Answers for each item of the tool ranged from 1 (“novice” physicians) to 5 (“expert” physicians). An overall summary score (range: 37-185) and a subscale summary score for each domain were calculated for each participant. General linear model was used to assess the association of physicians’ self-perceived level of competencies with covariates.Results: The internal consistency of the whole scale (37 items) was Cronbach’s alpha=0.98. Mean summary score of the 37-item instrument and subscale summary scores were all higher in men than in women. In multivariable-adjusted models, mean level of self-perceived competencies was higher among older physicians, in men, those with &amp;gt;10 years of working experience, physicians serving &amp;gt;2500 people, specialized physicians and those involved in training activities.Conclusion: Our study provides useful evidence on the self-assessed level of competencies of primary health care physicians in post-war Kosovo. Future studies in Kosovo and other transitional settings should identify the main determinants of possible gaps in self-perceived levels of physicians’ competencies vis-à-vis the level of physicians’ competencies from patients’ perspective.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlag</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1785</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/seejph-1785</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume II, 2014</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume II, 2014</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1785/1706</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 Fitim Skeraj, Katarzyna Czabanowska, Gazmend Bojaj, Genc Burazeri</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>