<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>1787</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Sex-differences in socioeconomic status and health-seeking behaviour among tuberculosis patients in transitional Albania in 2012-2013</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Kurti, Vera</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Hafizi, Hasan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Kurt, Bardhyl</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Kurti, Vera</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Hafizi, Hasan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Kurti, Bardhyl</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">access to health care</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Albania</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">case detection rate</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">health seeking behaviour</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">pulmonary tuberculosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">sex-differences</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">socioeconomic characteristics</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Aim: There is little scientific evidence about the main determinants of sex discrepancies in tuberculosis rates in Albania. The aim of this study was to assess the sex-differences in socioeconomic characteristics, knowledge and attitudes about tuberculosis and access to health care among tuberculosis patients in Albania, a transitional country in the Western Balkans.Methods: Our analysis involved all the new cases of pulmonary tuberculosis diagnosed in Albania during the period June 2012 – June 2013 (N=197; 69% males; overall mean age: 44±19 years). The recording and reporting system of tuberculosis cases was performed according to the WHO and EuroTB Surveillance guidelines. Information on socioeconomic characteristics of the patients, knowledge and attitudes about tuberculosis and access to health care was also collected. Logistic regression was used to assess the correlates of sex-differences among tuberculosis patients.Results: In multivariable-adjusted models, female sex was positively related to unemployment (OR=3.7, 95%CI=1.8-7.7), bad living conditions (OR=3.0, 95%CI=1.4-6.5), a longer distance to health care facility (OR=3.0, 95%CI=1.4-6.3), a lower level of knowledge about tuberculosis (OR=3.1, 95%CI=1.3-7.1) and a higher level of stigma against tuberculosis (OR=3.6, 95%CI=1.6-7.9).Conclusion: Our study informs about selected correlates of sex-differences in tuberculosis rates in post-communist Albania. Future studies should more vigorously explore determinants of sex-differences in tuberculosis rates in countries of the Western Balkans.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlag</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1787</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/seejph-1787</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume II, 2014</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume II, 2014</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1787/1708</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 Vera Kurti, Hasan Hafizi, Bardhyl Kurt, Vera Kurti, Hasan Hafizi, Bardhyl Kurti</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>