<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>1801</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">The South Eastern Europe Health Network: A model for regional collaboration in public health</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Ruseva, Maria</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Chichevalieva, Snezhana</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Harris, Meggan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Kostova, Neda Milevska</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Jakubowski, Elke</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Kluge, Hans</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Martin-Moreno, Jose M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">collaborative networks</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">health systems</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">public health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">regional cooperation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern Europe</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Inter-country alliances, articulated through regional approaches, have increasingly been used to drive economic development and social progress in the past several decades. The South Eastern Europe Health Network (SEEHN) stands out among these types of initiatives for the tangible improvements it has achieved in regional governance for health, with several important lessons for public health leaders worldwide. This review paper, written by several key participants in SEEHN operation, follows the main milestones in network development, including its foundation under the Stability Pact’s Initiative for Social Cohesion and the three ministerial forums that have shaped its evolution, in order to show how it can constitute a model for regional collaboration in public health. Herewith we summarise the main accomplishments of the network and highlight the keys to its success, drawing lessons that both international bodies and other regions may use in their own design of collaborative initiatives in health and in other areas of public policy.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlagublishing House</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1801</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/seejph-1801</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume III, 2015</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume III, 2015</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1801/1722</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 Maria Ruseva, Snezhana Chichevalieva, Meggan Harris, Neda Milevska Kostova, Elke Jakubowski, Hans Kluge, Jose M. Martin-Moreno</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>