<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>1814</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Reaction to political and socioeconomic transition and self-perceived health status in the adult population of Gjilan region, Kosovo</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Qazimi, Musa</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Cakerri, Luljeta</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Tahiri, Zejdush</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Burazeri, Genc</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">attitude to transition</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Gjilan</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Kosovo</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">psychosocial factors</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">reaction to transition</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">self-perceived health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">self-rated health</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Aim: The objective of our study was to assess the association of reaction to political and socioeconomic transition with self-perceived general health status in adult men and women in a region of Kosovo, a post-war country in the Western Balkans which has proclaimed independence in 2008.Methods: This was a cross-sectional study carried out in Gjilan region of Kosovo in 2014, including a representative sample of 867 primary health care users aged ≥35 years (419 men aged 54.3±10.9 years and 448 women aged 54.0±10.1 years; overall response rate: 87%). Reaction to political and socioeconomic aspects of transition was assessed by a three-item scale (trichotomized in the analysis into positive attitude, intermediate attitude, and negative attitude towards transition), which was previously used in the neighbouring Albania. Self-reported health status was measured on a 5-point scale which was dichotomized in the analysis into “good” vs. “poor” health. Demographic and socioeconomic data were also collected. Binary logistic regression was used to assess the association of reaction to transition with self-rated health status.Results: In crude/unadjusted models, negative attitude to transition was a “strong” predictor of poor self-perceived health (OR=2.5, 95%CI=1.7-3.8). Upon multivariable adjustment for all the demographic factors and socioeconomic characteristics, the association was attenuated and was only borderline statistically significant (OR=1.6, 95%CI=1.0-2.6, P=0.07).Conclusion: Our findings indicate an important association between reaction to transition and self-perceived health status in the adult population of the newly independent Kosovo. Policymakers and decision-makers in post-war countries such as Kosovo should be aware of the health effects of attitudes towards political and socioeconomic aspects of transition, which is seemingly an important psychosocial factor.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlagublishing House</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-11-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1814</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/seejph-1814</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume IV, 2015</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume IV, 2015</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1814/1735</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 Musa Qazimi, Luljeta Cakerri, Zejdush Tahiri, Genc Burazeri</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>