<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>1850</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Socio-demographic factors and selected clinical characteristics of patients with retinal vein occlusions in transitional Albania</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Rustani-Batku, Manushaqe</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Tonuzi, Ali</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Albania</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">clinical profile</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">ophthalmology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">retinal vein occlusion</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">socio-demographic factors.</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Aim: The aim of our study was to assess the distribution of socio-demographic factors and the clinical profile of individuals diagnosed with retinal vein occlusion (RVO) in Albania, a former communist country in South-eastern Europe which has been undergoing a rapid transition in the past decades.Methods: This study was carried out in 2013-2016 at the Primary Health Care Centre No. 2 in Tirana municipality, which is the capital of Albania. During this timeframe, on the whole, 44 patients were diagnosed with RVO at this primary health care centre (17 women and 27 men; overall mean age: 69.5±11.5 years). The diagnosis of RVO was based on signs and symptoms indicating a quick reduction of the sight (vision), fundoscopy, fluorescein angiography and the optical coherence tomography. Data on socio-demographic factors and clinical characteristics were also gathered for each study participant.Results: The prevalence of glaucoma was considerably higher in men than in women (67% vs. 24%, respectively, P=0.01). Diabetic retinopathy was somehow more prevalent in women than in men (18% vs. 11%, respectively), whereas an opposite finding was noted for the presence of hypertensive retinopathy (6% vs. 11%, respectively). The prevalence of cataract was higher in female patients compared with their male counterparts (18% vs. 7%, respectively, P=0.36). Both macular oedema and papillary oedema were almost equally distributed in men and in women (22% vs. 18% and 4% vs. 6%, respectively). All female patients had comorbid conditions compared to 85% of their male counterparts (P=0.15). The prevalence of hypertension was almost identical in both sexes (52% in men vs. 53% in women), whereas the prevalence of diabetes was somehow higher in men than in women (26% vs. 18%, respectively).  Conclusion: This is one of the very few studies informing about the distribution of socio-demographic factors and selected clinical characteristics of individuals diagnosed with RVO in transitional Albania. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlag</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-03-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1850</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/seejph-1850</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume VII, 2017</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume VII, 2017</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1850/1771</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2017 Manushaqe Rustani-Batku, Ali Tonuzi</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>