<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/1860</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-07-01T14:37:07Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>seejph:LED</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="en-US">High level Communiqué from the InterAction Council</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Lueddeke, George</dc:creator>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Dear Colleagues, Here is a link to a copy of a high level Communiqué from the InterActionCouncil that may also be of interest to SEEJPH readers. As you may be aware, the Council brings together former world leaders (heads of government and senior officials) and focuses on issues related, among others, to global security and has been examining the role of health security over the last few years. At this year’s meeting (30-31 May), co-chaired by HE Obasanjo from Nigeria and HE Bertie Ahern from Ireland, the session on Planetary Health, coordinated by Professor John Wyn Owen, resulted in the endorsement of the “Dublin Charter for One Health”. Dr Joanna Nurse presented on the policy implications of Planetary and One Health in this session and is tasked by the InterAction Council with advancing the One Health Charter in collaboration with key partners.  Below is a summary of the main actions in the Charter for One Health that may in due course help to inform trans-disciplinary research, education and practice at national, regional and global levels with a view to sustaining people and planet health and well-being.  Your comments on how best to advance these key areas are requested-i.e. please let us know what is already happening, gaps and suggestions for how to advance the following: Strengthening multi-sector solutions for the SDGs - the One Health approach has the potential to act as a unifying theme;Resilience to emerging threats -including AMR, disease outbreaks, climate change and environmental impacts;Mainstreaming One Health within public health systems for UHC -including environmental health;Strengthen One Health Governance mechanisms for systems reform;Building leadership for One Health for future generations; Establish an independent accountability mechanism for advancing action on One Health. Please send your comment to glueddeke@aol.com by 10 July.  Many thanks and best wishes!  George Lueddeke PhD</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlag</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2017-07-07</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1860</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/seejph-1860</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume VIII, 2017</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume VIII, 2017</dc:source>
      <dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1860/1781</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2017 George Lueddeke</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
