<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>1877</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Geriatric curriculum at faculties of medicine in Indonesia</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Surjadi, Charles</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Jani, Dwi</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Langoday, Ursula Yunita</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">faculty of medicine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">geriatric competency</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Indonesia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">teaching geriatrics.</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Aim: In Indonesia, the elderly population is growing rapidly and will comprise 35 million in 2035. The aim of this study was to assess how geriatric training is organised in medical faculties in Indonesia. Methods: In 2017, we asked through questionnaires the vice deans of the faculties of medicine about their perceptions towards health and ageing and how they organized the geriatric training in their respective schools. Overall, we obtained data from 32 out of 71 (45.1%) faculties of medicine. Results: All respondents perceived geriatrics as an important issue for faculties of medicine. Only 12 (37.5%) faculties employ geriatric specialists, 28 (87.5%) teach geriatrics at the undergraduate level, and 12 (40.6%) at postgraduate level, whereas 4 (12.5%) universities teach at specialty level. Conversely, at undergraduate level, only 18 (64.2%) faculties include the ‘geriatric giants’, and 5 (17.8%) include ageism. There are 13 (46.4%) geriatric classes implemented through skill laboratories, 5 (17.8%) through geriatric policlinics, and 4 (14.3%) through geriatric wards.Conclusion: Attention to geriatric training among medical schools in Indonesia has to be improved. At national level, there should be a more specific formulation of geriatric competencies and how they can be operationalised. Geriatric training is recommended to prepare lecturers in medical faculties. Related to the content of aging curriculum, geriatric issues, attitudes towards aging, and ageism should be addressed.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlag</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-07-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1877</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/seejph-1877</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume X, 2018</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume X, 2018</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1877/1797</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2018 Charles Surjadi, Dwi Jani, Ursula Yunita Langoday</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>