<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>1888</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Overweight and obesity among women living in peri-urban areas in West Africa</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Malik, Koussoh Simone</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Adoubi, Anicet</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Kouadio, Kouamé</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Kouamé, Jérôme</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Hounsa, Annita</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Sackou, Julie</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">abdominal obesity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Africa</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">central obesity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">overweight</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">women.</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US"> Aim: This study assessed selected correlates of overweight and obesity among women in a sub-urban population of Abidjan, Côte d’Ivoire.Methods: A cross-sectional study was conducted during April-May, 2014 in Abobo-Anonkoi 3, a peri-urban city of Abidjan in Côte d’Ivoire. Women of 18 years and older healthy in appearance were randomly recruited from households. Overweight and obesity were measured by BMI respectively greater or equal to 25 and 30 kg/m2. Abdominal obesity was defined by waist to hip ratio greater or equal to 0.80. The level of physical activity was evaluated by the IPAQ questionnaire and the blood pressure according to the criteria of the JNC7 report. A regression analysis of the associated factors with overweight and obesity (age, marital status, level of study, level of physical activity, blood pressure, and socioeconomic status) was carried out.Results: We visited 486 households in which 398 women were approached and 327 agreed to participate in the survey. The average age was 35.25 ± 12.4 years. The prevalence of overweight was 27.2% and that of obesity was 19.6%; 72.2%of women had abdominal obesity. The prevalence of abdominal obesity was 90.6% among obese people. Age (p=0.006), marital status (p=0.002) and blood pressure (p=0.004) were significantly associated with obesity. With regard to abdominal obesity, there was a significant association of educational level in addition to the above factors.Conclusion: Overweight and obesity are a reality in this population of Côte d’Ivoire and about one in five people are affected by the scourge of obesity.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlagublishing House</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-09-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1888</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/seejph-1888</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume XII, 2019</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume XII, 2019</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/1888/1808</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2019 Koussoh Simone Malik, Anicet Adoubi, Kouamé Kouadio, Jérôme Kouamé, Annita Hounsa, Julie Sackou</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>