<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/3129</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-07-01T14:37:06Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>seejph:ART</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Successful reduction of premature mortality in the Russian Federation and the countries around the Baltic Sea working together on Health and Social Well-being</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Chernyavskiy, Valery </dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Wenzel, Helmut </dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Mikhailova, Julia </dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ivanova, Alla </dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Zemlyanova, Elena </dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Bjegovic-Mikanovic, Vesna </dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Mikhailov, Alexander </dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Laaser, Ulrich </dc:creator>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">gap analysis, northern dimension, North West Federal Okrug, premature mortality, public health, Russian Federation.</dc:subject>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Context: The ‘Northern Dimension on Public Health and Social Well-being’ is a platform for dialogue and cooperation of countries around the Baltic Sea, established in 2003, guided by the Sustainable Development Goal 3 on Health and Social Well-being and the Strategy for the Baltic Sea Region of the European Union adopted in 2009. In this paper we determine the overall progress of the Russian Federation and its North West Federal Okrugin in particular, with regard to the reduction of mortality.
Methods: For the purpose of inter-country comparison and progress over time we make use of age-standardised Potential Years of Life Lost (PYLL) applied to quantifiable strategic targets, the Sustainable Development Goal 3 on Health and Social Well-being and the European Union Strategy of the Baltic Sea Region. A gap analysis is performed to determine whether the target achievement is in delay or on track.
Results: With reference to the baseline of 2009 – corresponding to the most relevant recent period 2009-2020 respectively 2009-2030 – the Russian Federation as a whole is on track achieving the two strategic targets in advance by 2.7 years. For the North West Federal Okrug around St. Petersburg and Kaliningrad bordering the Baltic Sea the target achievement is estimated to be 4.8 and 10.8 years in advance of the deadlines 2020 and 2030. In comparison to the Baltic Sea states the Russian Federation takes a middle position after Estonia, Latvia and Finland. The early target achievement is confirmed if the period 2003-2020 respectively 2003-2030 is considered.
Conclusion: Although the region is progressing there may be a slowdown towards 2030. A careful analysis is required to determine to which degree the activities of the Partnership for Health and Social Well-being have contributed to the success and what should be proposed to increase the impact on premature mortality.</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlag</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2019-10-30</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/3129</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/seejph-3129</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume XIII, 2020</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume XIII, 2020</dc:source>
      <dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/3129/3176</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2019 Valery  Chernyavskiy, Helmut  Wenzel, Julia  Mikhailova, Alla  Ivanova, Elena  Zemlyanova, Vesna  Bjegovic-Mikanovic, Alexander  Mikhailov, Ulrich  Laaser</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
