<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>3631</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Clinical and epidemiological evaluation of Tuberculosis in Albania during the period 2009-2018</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Peposhi, Ilir </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Tafa, Holta </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Bardhi, Donika </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Hafizi, Hasan</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">drug resistance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">epidemiology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">incidence</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">treatment outcomes</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">tuberculosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Aim: To estimate the clinical and epidemiological pattern of Tuberculosis (TB) in Albania over the period 2009-2018.
Methods: A retrospective analysis of clinical and epidemiological data based on TB individual notification forms during the period 2009-2018.
Results: During the 10-years period, TB incidence increased from 14 to 15.5, but without a significant increasing trend. The total number of TB cases increased from 440 to 447. The proportion of extra-pulmonary TB decreased from 32% to 25% in 2018 (p=0.015), with and average mean change of 29 cases. Males prevail among TB cases and male-to-female ratio ranges from 2:1 to 3:1. Drug susceptibility testing (DST) was carried out depending on the availability of the reagents and there were 54%, 18% and 96% culture cases confirmed positive in 2009, 2014 and 2019, respectively. The overall treatment completion rate was 85% and 88.2% in 2009 and 2018, respectively. However, there was a significant drop in cured cases from 26% in 9.3%, whereas the percentage of deaths has increased from 0.5% in 4.1%. All treatment outcomes exhibited a significant change (p&amp;lt;0.001).
&amp;nbsp;
Conclusion: TB continues to be a public health challenge in Albania regardless of the seemingly generally stable epidemiological situation.
&amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;
Conflicts of interest: None declared.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlagublishing House</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-08-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/3631</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/seejph-3631</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume XIV, 2020</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume XIV, 2020</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/3631/3710</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2020 Ilir  Peposhi, Holta  Tafa, Donika  Bardhi, Hasan Hafizi</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>