<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>4240</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Assessment of the prevalence and risk factors of low back pain in operating room health workers: An observational study in Italy</dc:title>
	<dc:creator> Brauneis, Stefano</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Sorrentino, Enza </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Di Lisa, Vincenza </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator> Galluccio, Gabriella</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator> Piras, Barbara</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator> Carella, Francesca</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator> Palozzi, Edoardo</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Generali, Carmela </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Maggiacomo, Simona</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator> D’Aurelio, Silvia</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Backhaus, Insa </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>La Torre, Filippo </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Villani, Ciro </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>La Torre, Giuseppe </dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">health workers</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">low back pain</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">occupational low back pain</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">operating room health professionals</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">prevention</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Aim: The aim of this study was to assess the prevalence of low back pain (LBP) among healthprofessionals and the possible risk factors.
Methods: The study was carried out from April 2018 to October 2018 among all health workers of the Orthopaedic Clinic and the Emergency Department of “Policlinico Umberto I” in Rome. LBP was assessed using the Nordic Questionnaire Musculoskeletal Disorders in the section on lumbar pain. The type of physical activity carried out as prevention was investigated by use of the International Physical Activity Questionnaires. The overall state of health and lifestyle was deter- mined by the Short Form 12-item Health Survey. Job satisfaction and perceived work stress were assessed through the 15-questions of Karasek’s Questionnaire. The intensity of the low back pain was assessed using a Numerical Rating Scale. A univariate analysis was conducted to assess the associations between socio-demographic and working variables. Multiple logistic regression mod- els were used to assess independent correlates of LBP.
Results: One hundred thirteen subjects were enrolled, 52 women and 61 men. The annual period- prevalence of lumbar musculoskeletal disorder was found on 79.6% of participants with LBP. Mean value evidence of NRS was 2.66. The highest LBP risk over the 12 months was found in groups with high job demand (OR = 1.18; 95%CI: 1.01 – 1.38), low decision-making opportunities (for decision latitude OR = 0.87; (0-76 – 1.0), and low levels of physical activity (OR = 0.75; 95%CI: 0.64 – 0.89).
Conclusion: The working environment is a potential risk factor for the development of LBP and is suitable for prevention programmes. The protective effect of physical activity and work-related stress management indicate room for improvements for the prevention of LBP in these HCWs.
Conflicts of interest: None declared.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlag</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-03-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/4240</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11576/seejph-4240</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume XVI, 2021</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume XVI, 2021</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/4240/4172</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 Stefano  Brauneis, Enza  Sorrentino, Vincenza  Di Lisa, Gabriella  Galluccio, Barbara  Piras, Francesca  Carella, Edoardo  Palozzi, Carmela  Generali, Simona Maggiacomo, Silvia  D’Aurelio, Insa  Backhaus, Filippo  La Torre, Ciro  Villani, Giuseppe  La Torre</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>