<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>4318</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Post Covid-19 Agenda: Maximizing human resources for health towards Universal Health Coverage in Africa</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Amedari , McKing I. </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator> Ejidike, Ifunanya Carista</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">covid-19</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Human Resources for Health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Supportive Supervision</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Market factors, Information Technology</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Aim: To analyse options for maximising the capacity of human resources for health to achieve Universal Health Coverage (UHC) in Africa.
Methods: Articles were retrieved from a Pubmed search and additional snowballing was conducted to provide other relevant sources. Further utilizations were made of Campbell's modified framework of the Human Resources for Health (HRH) and Universal Health Coverage with the WHO labour market dynamics framework for Universal Health Coverage. Four sub-themes viz improved HRH performance, Labour Market Factors, Rural Health Workers Retention Factors, and Information Technology Factors were analysed.
Results: Labour market factors such as the dynamics of demand and supply of health workers determine the availability of health workers. Supportive supervision enables the health workers to improve in their performance and enhance optimised utilisation of available resources. This supervision can be more effective by complementing it with tools such as information technology that focus on improving the quality of health care, considering the growth in the number of internet and broadband users in the continent.
Conclusion: Expanding the training opportunities for health workers and also increasing the funding to human resources for health are useful policy options to consider. Cost-effective approaches such as a focus on community health committees which stimulate the demand for health services in rural communities to tackle the disproportionate distribution of health workers should be considered in the context of the uncertain economic aftermath of the covid-19 outbreak.
Sources of Funding
Nil
Acknowledgement
We express profound gratitude to Prof Flavia Senkubuge for providing technical help and writing assistance during the preparation of this manuscript. We also appreciate Dr. Aborisade Adetayo for assisting with editing of the manuscript.
Conflicts of Interest
The authors declare no conflict of interest.
Author Contributions
MIA drafted the entire manuscript. ICE provided a critical review and made substantial contributions to the design of the manuscript.
&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlagublishing House</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-05-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/4318</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11576/seejph-4318</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Special Volume No. 2, 2021: Announcing the Hideyo Noguchi Africa Prize (1st edition) </dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Special Volume No. 2, 2021: Announcing the Hideyo Noguchi Africa Prize (1st edition) </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/4318/4276</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 McKing I.  Amedari , Ifunanya Carista  Ejidike</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>