<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>4425</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Voluntary blood donation promotion in Haute Matsiatra region of  Madagascar</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Fenomanana, Jocia </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Ramaminiaina, Heritiana Gisèle </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Randriatsarafara, Fidiniaina Mamy </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Randriamanantany, Zely Arivelo </dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">&amp;nbsp;
Aims: &amp;nbsp;Access to sufficient, secure supplies of blood and safe transfusion services is an essential part of any strong health system. The Haute Matsiatra region has a need for blood and blood products that exceeds current availability (only 7% of needs are met). The aim of this study ls to assess community knowledge, attitude, and practice regarding voluntary blood donation in order to identify the obstacles.
&amp;nbsp;
Methods: We have conducted a community-based cross-sectional study from 26th to 31th July 2019 within a sample of 300 subjects using a structured questionnaire and face-to-face interview. Data were analyzed using R software version 4.0.2.
&amp;nbsp;
Results: All participants were unanimous about vital role of blood so that 62.3% were willing to donate blood but only 13% have ever donated blood. The majority of respondents (60.0%) had never heard sensitization about blood donation. The reason for non-donation were related to fears of needlestick injuries during the blood collect (38.3%), fear of blood borne diseases (17%), the lack of sensitization (6%). There was a positive significant relationship between level of education and willingness to donate blood (p-value &amp;lt;0, 05). The likelihood of blood donation was found to be higher among male participant 28 (71.8%) p&amp;lt;0.05, and among &amp;gt;45 years group (21.4 %) p= 0.03. Among those who ever donated blood, only 37 (26.6%) of them have received sensitization about donation.
&amp;nbsp;
Conclusion: There is growing interest in blood donation among the population. Activities to promote blood volunteer donation should take into account the demotivating reasons for blood donation.
&amp;nbsp;
Source of funding&amp;nbsp;: None
&amp;nbsp;
Conflict of interest statement: The authors report no conflicts of interest in this work.
&amp;nbsp;
Authors’ contributions&amp;nbsp;: All authors contributed toward data analysis, drafting and critically revising the paper and agree to be accountable for all aspects of the work.
&amp;nbsp;
Acknowledgments&amp;nbsp;: We thank all those who, directly or indirectly, have contributed to this publication.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlagublishing House</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-05-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/4425</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11576/seejph-4425</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Special Volume No. 2, 2021: Announcing the Hideyo Noguchi Africa Prize (1st edition) </dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Special Volume No. 2, 2021: Announcing the Hideyo Noguchi Africa Prize (1st edition) </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/4425/4264</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 Jocia  Fenomanana, Heritiana Gisèle  Ramaminiaina, Fidiniaina Mamy  Randriatsarafara, Zely Arivelo  Randriamanantany</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>