<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>4447</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Applying innovative strategies to achieve Universal Health Coverage in the African Region</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Leufak, Arlette Mouako </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Ndwandwe, Duduzile </dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Innovative strategies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Universal health coverage</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">African Region</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Universal health coverage is defined as ensuring that all people have access to needed health services of sufficient quality to be effective while ensuring that these services do not expose the user the financial hardship. Universal health coverage includes three related objectives: equity in access to health services (everyone who needs services should get them, not only those who can pay for them); the quality of health services should be good enough to improve the health of those receiving services; and people should be protected against financial risk, ensuring that the cost of using services does not put people at risk of financial harm. Africa still has a long way to go to achieve these objectives. Many barriers limit the progress of the African Region towards building the robust health systems needed for universal health coverage. Such barriers include poor infrastructure, high out-of-pocket payments and catastrophic health expenditures, shortages and inequitable distribution of qualified healthcare workers, poor quality of care delivery, high cost of quality medicines, and lack of innovative technologies appropriate to the range of settings where care is delivered, health financing and governance. This paper aims to propose innovative strategies that could be applied to improve health systems in the Africa Region, which progress towards the continent attaining universal health coverage. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlag</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-05-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/4447</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11576/seejph-4447</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Special Volume No. 2, 2021: Announcing the Hideyo Noguchi Africa Prize (1st edition) </dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Special Volume No. 2, 2021: Announcing the Hideyo Noguchi Africa Prize (1st edition) </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/4447/4270</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 Arlette Mouako  Leufak, Duduzile  Ndwandwe</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>