<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/4448</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-05-31T13:28:15Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>seejph:REV</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Towards Universal Health Coverage in Africa: Relevance of Telemedicine and Mobile Clinics</dc:title>
      <dc:creator> Adedeji, Oluwakorede Joshua</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Babatunde, Yusuf Olalekan </dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ibrahim, Abdulmumin Damilola </dc:creator>
      <dc:creator> Adebisi, Yusuff Adebayo</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Lucero-Prisno III, Don Eliseo </dc:creator>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Universal Health Coverage</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Telemedicine</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Information and Communication Technology</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Mobile clinic</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Africa</dc:subject>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Access to essential healthcare services is limited in Africa, resulting in preventable mortalities. Telemedicine, which can be defined as the use of information and communication technologies in the delivery of healthcare services, is applied in various fields of medicine and at multiple times. Some telemedicine projects have been implemented in different African countries. Some successes were recorded, as well as failures. Despite challenges, such as high cost, that inhibit telemedicine coverage, telemedicine still presents excellent opportunities in increasing access to basic healthcare and expert services. Mobile clinics provide the opportunity to expand access to health services across a region. They can be implemented as an extension of fixed1hospitals that are often situated away from remote villages, serve in the heart of communities, and aid in preventive screenings and epidemiological monitoring. Africa has limited resources but leveraging these existing resources most cost-effectively is key to achieving universal health coverage in the region.
Source of funding: None
Conflicting Interest: The authors declare no conflict of interest.
Authors' Contributions: Oluwakorede Joshua Adedeji conceptualized the study. Oluwakorede Joshua Adedeji, Yusuf Olalekan Babatunde and Abdulmumin Damilola Ibrahim acquired, analysed and interpreted the data for the work. Yusuff Adebayo Adebisi and Don Eliseo Lucero-Prisno III revised it critically for important intellectual content. All authors agree to be accountable for all aspects of the work in ensuring that all questions related to the accuracy or integrity of any part of the work are appropriately investigated and resolved.
&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlag</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2021-05-17</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/4448</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.11576/seejph-4448</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Special Volume No. 2, 2021: Announcing the Hideyo Noguchi Africa Prize (1st edition) </dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Special Volume No. 2, 2021: Announcing the Hideyo Noguchi Africa Prize (1st edition) </dc:source>
      <dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/4448/4271</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 Oluwakorede Joshua  Adedeji, Yusuf Olalekan  Babatunde, Abdulmumin Damilola  Ibrahim, Yusuff Adebayo  Adebisi, Don Eliseo  Lucero-Prisno III</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
