<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>4477</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Contribution of Information-Education-Communication in the adoption of Universal Health Coverage by the populations in the Economic and Monetary Community of Central Africa in 2020.</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Ledaga, Nathalie Ambounda </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Mamche , Robertine </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Woromogo , Sylvain Honore </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Saba Antaon, Jesse Saint </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Saar , Fatou Sow </dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Universal Health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Coverage</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Central Africa</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Aims: This study aims to assess the knowledge of people from Central Africa about Universal Health Coverage and show the contribution of Information-Education-Communication for its adoption.
&amp;nbsp;
Methods: a cross-sectional analytical study across 4 of 6 Central African Countries was conducted. Independent variables are sociodemographic characteristics. Dependent variables are knowledge about Information-Education-Communication and Universal Health Coverage. The questionnaire was disseminated by WhatsApp images or word file or copy/paste of the text and send to the contacted and trained focal points. From the Smartphone, the filmed or transferred data were entered into a CSpro 5.0 input form. Mean score calculations and Odd Ratio with 95 % Confidence Interval for p &amp;lt; 0.005 were used to make associations.
&amp;nbsp;
Results: the Universal Health Coverage had never been heard of by 56.3% of the participants. The Universal Health Coverage was defined as health insurance by (43.9%), free care (30.3%). Respondents with secondary and higher education are more likely to have heard of the UHC than respondents with no education or those with elementary education [OR = 2.95 (1.01-8.64), p = 0.021] and [OR = 4.27 (1.50 – 12.16), p = 0.002] respectively.
&amp;nbsp;
Conclusion: 9.3% of the Economic and Monetary Community of Central Africa (CEMAC) population is aware of the Universal Health Coverage; 89.4% of these accept universal health coverage in their country, and 87.4% of them think that the Information Education Communication could enable better adherence to the Universal Health Communication. Implemention of Universal Health Coverage for the general population and adoption of Information-Education-Communication to promote Universal Health Coverage and pool efforts and affiliation procedures in the CEMAC zone is very important</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlag</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/4477</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11576/seejph-4477</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Special Volume No. 2, 2021: Announcing the Hideyo Noguchi Africa Prize (1st edition) </dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Special Volume No. 2, 2021: Announcing the Hideyo Noguchi Africa Prize (1st edition) </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/4477/4282</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 Nathalie Ambounda  Ledaga, Robertine  Mamche , Sylvain Honore  Woromogo , Jesse Saint  Saba Antaon, Fatou Sow  Saar </dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>