<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>5084</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Feasibility and clinical utility of Bates-Jensen wound assessment tool among nurses caring of patients having pressure ulcers</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Younis, Wejdan Y</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Abdalrahim, Maysoon S</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Zeilani, Ruqayya S</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Albusoul, Randa</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Alosaimi, Dalyal</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Hamdan-Mansour, Ayman M</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Bates-Jensen Wound Assessment Tool</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">clinical utility</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">feasibility</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">wound assessment</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Aims: One of the vital roles of nurses is to perform pressure ulcer risk assessment that enables them to appropriately assess and track healing progress of wound and pressure ulcers among patients. Our aim was to assess the feasibility and clinical utility of the Bates-Jensen Wound Assessment Tool (BWAT) among nurses caring of patients with pressure ulcer.
Methods: A descriptive cross-sectional design used to collect data from 177 registered nurses caring of patients who developed or have a risk of developing pressure ulcers working in three hospitals in Jordan.
Results: The mean feasibility score of the BWAT was 28.3 out of 36 (SD=3.4) with a median score of 29. Most of nurses reported that the BWAT was easy to use on a scale of 1-4 (best) (M=3.40/4, SD=0.62) and can successfully assess wound characteristics (M=3.40/4, SD=0.59). The mean utility score of the BWAT was 21.3 out of 28 (SD=2.7) with a median of 21. Nurses had a perception that using the BWAT enhances care of patients with wounds (M=3.36/4, SD=0.61) and makes communication easier between nurses and physicians.&amp;nbsp;
Conclusion: This study provided evidence that support the use of the Bates-Jensen Wound Assessment Tool for patients with pressure ulcer. Nurses perceived BWAT as easy to use, understandable, and relevant for assessing patients with pressure ulcers.
&amp;nbsp;
Funding statement: This work was supported by supported and funded by The Deanship of Scientific Research at The University of Jordan, Amman, Jordan [number1953/2017/19].
&amp;nbsp;
Conflicts of interest: The authors declare no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship and publication of this study.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlagublishing House</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-01-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/5084</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11576/seejph-5084</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume XVII, 2021</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume XVII, 2021</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/5084/4698</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 Wejdan Y Younis, Maysoon S Abdalrahim, Ruqayya S Zeilani, Randa Albusoul, Dalyal Alosaimi, Ayman M Hamdan-Mansour</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>