<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>5091</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Factors Affecting the Uptake of COVID-19 Vaccine among Dubai Airport's Professionals</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Taryam, Manal</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Alawadhi, Dhoha </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Aburayya, Ahmad</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Mubarak, Sara</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Aljasmi, Maryam</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator> Salloum, Said A</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Mouzaek, Talal</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">adverse effects</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Binary Logistic Regression Model</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">COVID-19 Pandemic</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Dubai Airport</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">uptake vaccine</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Aim: Comprehending the elements that influence COVID-19 vaccination acceptability and recognizing expediters for vaccination decisions are critical components of developing effective ways to increase vaccine coverage in the general population. This study aims to investigate the main factors affecting COVID-19 vaccination uptake among Dubai 'Airport's employees. In addition, it seeks to explore the main signs and symptoms that appeared on vaccinated employees after taking the COVID-19 vaccination, hence, track the vaccine's safety.
&amp;nbsp;
Methods: Employees at Dubai's airport in the United Arab Emirates (UAE), mainly in Dubai, provided data. To gather data online utilising the Google Forms platform, a questionnaire was used as the main quantitative tool. As 2000 questionnaires got distributed, 1007 employees participated in the survey, yielding a 50.4% response rate.
&amp;nbsp;
Results: The results show that employees overwhelmingly agree with the assertion that the factors of accessibility and affordability have a significant effect on their decision to receive the COVID-19 vaccine, followed by a trust in vaccine, knowledge, vaccine safety, advice and information, and beliefs on the vaccine. In this study, the agreement level on factors affecting the COVID-19 vaccine uptake was found significantly to be higher in females (88.6%) who were married (91.6%) and those aged over 60 years (89.2%) at P &amp;lt;.05. In addition, the results show that 53.7% of vaccinated staff was found to have one or more side effects of the vaccine, where none of them was hospitalized after immunization. The binary logistic regression analysis in this study shows that females were two times more likely to have 'vaccine's symptoms after vaccination than males (Exp (B): 1.6; 95%CI: 1.127 - 2.351, P&amp;lt; .01). It further reveals that participants in the age group over 50 were three times more likely to have 'vaccine's symptoms after vaccination than participants in the age group 20-29 (Exp (B): 2.9; 95%CI: 2.497-9.681, P&amp;lt; .001). Finally, it indicates that individuals with previous SARS-CoV-2 infection were 2 times more likely to have 'vaccine's symptoms after vaccination than those without known past infection (Exp (B): 1.9; 95%CI: 1.272 - 2.542, P&amp;lt; .01).
&amp;nbsp;
Conclusion: There are several factors that playing a significant role in population’s decision to receive the COVID-19 vaccine, where the accessibility and affordability factors were found to have the greatest effect on their decision to uptake the vaccine. The current study concluded that COVID-19 vaccination is safe and that adverse effects from a vaccine are usually modest and affected by several factors such as age, gender, and COVID-19 infection history.
&amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;
Conflicts of interest: None declared.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlag</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-01-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/5091</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11576/seejph-5091</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume XVII, 2021</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Volume XVII, 2021</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/5091/4700</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 Manal Taryam, Dhoha  Alawadhi, Ahmad Aburayya, Sara Mubarak, Maryam Aljasmi, Said A  Salloum, Talal Mouzaek</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>