<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>5330</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Tuberculosis literacy and stigma: female activists in five areas with the lowest treatment success rate in Semarang, Indonesia</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Mubarokah, Kismi </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Nurjanah, Nurjanah </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Handayani, Sri </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Astarini, Hermin Rhema </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Maharani, Adelia Wahyuningtyas </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Masitoh, Dewi </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Salisa, Merisha Dea </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Yulianah, Sri Dian </dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">literacy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">stigma</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">tuberculosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Background: The Case Detection Rate of Tuberculosis (TB) in Semarang city increased from 2014 to 2018, while the Treatment Success Rate declined. Low literacy can trigger stigma in society, especially among women, resulting in low awareness of suspect TB for treatment.
Objectives: The aims are to analyze the correlation between TB literacy and stigma expressed among female health and social activists.
Methods: Cross-sectional research was conducted in five public health centers with the lowest Treatment Success Rate (TSR). A valid and reliable self-administered online questionnaire collected data that involved 391 respondents predominantly in the urban areas. Rank Spearman test was used to analyze the data with a confidence interval of 95%.
Results: The respondents were mostly elderly (&amp;gt;45 years; 61.6%), health activists with high school graduation, didn't have a family with a health background and did not work. Most of them showed low TB literacy (Me:60; SD±6.62) and high stigma (Me: 76; SD±10.36). They were also difficult to access, understand, assess, and apply information about TB. Age (p.0.03; r.-0.110), being health activist (p.0.081; r.-0.088), and TB literacy (p.0.001; r.0.165) correlated significantly with stigma.
Conclusions: Public Health Center's officers require inserting literacy education materials related to stigma to form a comfortable support system for persons with TB.
Conflicts of interest: None declared.
Acknowledgment: Many thanks and appreciation to Semarang City of Health Governments, the 5 Public Health Centres, the Faculty of Health Science UDINUS, and AHLA (Asia Health Literacy Association) Indonesia Country Office Universitas Dian Nuswantoro</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Jacobs Verlagublishing House</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-03-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/5330</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11576/seejph-5330</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Special Volume No. 2, 2022: YOUNG INDONESIAN SCIENTISTS WRITE ON PUBLIC HEALTH </dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">South Eastern European Journal of Public Health (SEEJPH); Special Volume No. 2, 2022: YOUNG INDONESIAN SCIENTISTS WRITE ON PUBLIC HEALTH </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5248</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.seejph.com/index.php/seejph/article/view/5330/4899</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2022 Kismi  Mubarokah, Nurjanah  Nurjanah, Sri  Handayani, Hermin Rhema  Astarini, Adelia Wahyuningtyas  Maharani, Dewi  Masitoh, Merisha Dea  Salisa, Sri Dian  Yulianah</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>