<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>2413</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">Reflexive Begleitung von Studien-Praxis-Projekten und die Förderung von Reflexivität in (alternativen) Praxisphasen</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Reflexive  Supervision  of Study-Practice-Projects  and  the  Promotion  of Reflexivity in (Alternative) Practical Phases</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Kahlau, Joana</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Tietjen, Christina</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Reflexion</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Reflexivität</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">kollegiale Fallberatung</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Reflexionsmodell</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Praxisprojekte</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Praxisphasen</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Schul- und Unterrichtsentwicklung</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">reflection</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">reflexivity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">collegial case advice</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">models of reflection</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">practice-projects</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">practical phases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">school development</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">lesson planning development</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">Studien-Praxis-Projekte&amp;nbsp; sind&amp;nbsp; eine&amp;nbsp; innovative&amp;nbsp; Form&amp;nbsp; von Praxisprojekten, die im Rahmen der Qualitätsoffensive Lehrerbildung an der Universität Bremen entwickelt wurden. Studierende arbeiten hierbei mit Lehrkräften in einer Art Arbeitsgemeinschaft auf Zeit an von der Schule geäußerten Problemstellungen im Bereich Schul-&amp;nbsp; und Unterrichtsentwicklung. Hierbei geht es darum, im Sinne des „Reflective Practitioners“ (Schön, 1987) einen Ort der Entwicklungs- und Forschungsarbeit für Studierende zu gestalten, der in Bremen an das Praxissemester, das stärker auf das Unterrichten fokussiert, anschließt. Es handelt&amp;nbsp; sich hierbei also um ein alternatives Praxissetting, das additiv zum Praxissemester konzipiert ist. Zusätzlich zur Fokussierung auf den Kompetenzbereich des Innovierens (KMK, 2004) geht es explizit darum, diese Entwicklungsprojekte und die eigene Rolle darin zu reflektieren. Neben der Zielsetzung,&amp;nbsp; Reflexivität als Grundhaltung anzubahnen, wird auf dem Weg dorthin Reflexion als einzuübende Praxis begriffen.&amp;nbsp; Das&amp;nbsp; in&amp;nbsp; diesem&amp;nbsp; Rahmen&amp;nbsp; entwickelte&amp;nbsp; Seminarkonzept&amp;nbsp; soll&amp;nbsp; die&amp;nbsp; Studierenden durch Reflexionsanlässe bei ihrer Projektdurchführung begleiten. Einerseits wird die Diskussion über den Nutzen von Reflexion auf einer Metaebene angeregt. Andererseits wird auf Basis der eigenen, potenziell krisenhaften Projekterlebnisse Reflexion in Form von strukturierten und angeleiteten handlungspraktischen Reflexionsmethoden eingeübt. Diese Arbeit zielt sowohl auf die Wiederherstellung bzw. Veränderung der eigenen Handlungspraxis im Projekt ab als auch auf die fortlaufende individuelle Professionalisierung. Dieser Beitrag wird das Seminarkonzept detailliert&amp;nbsp; vorstellen.&amp;nbsp; Es&amp;nbsp; werden&amp;nbsp; insbesondere&amp;nbsp; die&amp;nbsp; Methoden&amp;nbsp; der&amp;nbsp; Begleitung,&amp;nbsp; die Formen der kollegialen Fallberatung und das theoriegestützte Reflexionsmodell in den&amp;nbsp; Blick&amp;nbsp; genommen.&amp;nbsp; Abschließend&amp;nbsp; wird&amp;nbsp; überlegt,&amp;nbsp; inwiefern&amp;nbsp; all&amp;nbsp; das&amp;nbsp; für&amp;nbsp; andere Praxisformen als das Praxissemester nutzbar ist.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">The&amp;nbsp; study-practice-project&amp;nbsp; is&amp;nbsp; an&amp;nbsp; innovative&amp;nbsp; format&amp;nbsp; of&amp;nbsp; practice-projects, which has been developed at the University of Bremen in the context of the “Qualitätsoffensive Lehrerbildung”. In a studygroup of a defined timespan, students cooperate with a teacher working on a concrete problem regarding school and&amp;nbsp; lesson&amp;nbsp; planning&amp;nbsp; development,&amp;nbsp; which&amp;nbsp; has&amp;nbsp; been&amp;nbsp; presented&amp;nbsp; by&amp;nbsp; this&amp;nbsp; specific school. Based on the concept of the “reflective practitioner” (Schön, 1987), the idea is to create a space for students wherein they can gather practical knowledge and&amp;nbsp; competence&amp;nbsp; in&amp;nbsp; the&amp;nbsp; field&amp;nbsp; of&amp;nbsp; school&amp;nbsp; development&amp;nbsp; as&amp;nbsp; well&amp;nbsp; as&amp;nbsp; research.&amp;nbsp; As&amp;nbsp; it takes place after the practical semester, where the focus is on teaching itself, it represents an alternative and additional practical setting. Beyond the competence of innovation (KMK, 2004), the underlying idea is to reflect upon the practiceproject as well as upon one’s own personal role within the project. Reflexivity is hereby understood not only as one’s own basic attitude but also as a practice itself, which needs to be well studied. The concept of the seminar developed within this context is to accompany the students by creating moments of re flection during the practical phase of their projects. On the one hand, the discussion about the advantages of reflection on a meta-level is encouraged. On the other hand, reflection&amp;nbsp; will&amp;nbsp; be&amp;nbsp; trained&amp;nbsp; by&amp;nbsp; looking&amp;nbsp; at&amp;nbsp; potentially&amp;nbsp; critical&amp;nbsp; practice&amp;nbsp; experiences&amp;nbsp; using structured and instructed methods of reflection. The aim is to professionally handle&amp;nbsp; the&amp;nbsp; critical&amp;nbsp; practice&amp;nbsp; experience&amp;nbsp; and&amp;nbsp; thereby&amp;nbsp; restore&amp;nbsp; one’s&amp;nbsp; own&amp;nbsp; ability&amp;nbsp; to&amp;nbsp; act within the project. It thus also aims at the individual professionalization process. This article presents the concept of the seminar in detail. We will focus on the methods&amp;nbsp; used&amp;nbsp; to&amp;nbsp; accompany&amp;nbsp; the&amp;nbsp; students&amp;nbsp; in&amp;nbsp; this practical&amp;nbsp; phase,&amp;nbsp; i.e.,&amp;nbsp; a form&amp;nbsp; of collegial case advice and a theory-based model of reflection. Finally, we will discuss its applicability for other formats of practical phases.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="de-DE">Bielefeld School of Education (BiSEd)</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-12-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="de-DE">Begutachteter Beitrag</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.herausforderung-lehrerinnenbildung.de/index.php/hlz/article/view/2413</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/hlz-2413</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">Herausforderung Lehrer*innenbildung - Zeitschrift zur Konzeption, Gestaltung und Diskussion; Bd. 1 Nr. 2 (2018): Studienprojekte im Praxissemester; 126-141</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Challenge Teacher Education; Vol. 1 No. 2 (2018): Student projects during internships in teacher education; 126-141</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2625-0675</dc:source>
	<dc:language>deu</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.herausforderung-lehrerinnenbildung.de/index.php/hlz/article/view/2413/2409</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">Copyright (c) 2018 Joana Kahlau, Christina Tietjen</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>