<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/2416</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-05-25T10:06:07Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>hlz:L2_KG</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">Interdisziplinäres Denken als Ziel und Mittel für Reflexivität in der Lehrer_innenbildung: Das Kooperationsprojekt „Forschendes Lernen im Praxissemester ─ interdisziplinär" (FLIP-I)</dc:title>
      <dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Interdisciplinary Thinking as Object and Means for Reflexivity in the Academic Education of Prospective Teachers: Das Kooperationsprojekt „Forschendes Lernen im Praxissemester ─ interdisziplinär" (FLIP-I)</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Falkenstörfer, Sophia</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Keeley, Caren</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Zepter, Alexandra Lavinia</dc:creator>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Interdisziplinäres Forschendes Lernen</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Interdisziplinäres Denken und Reflexivität</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Zwei-Disziplinen-Profilgruppe</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">interdisciplinary exploratory learning</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">interdisciplinary thinking and refelxivity</dc:subject>
      <dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">Im Praxissemester-Modell der Universität zu Köln werden alle Lehramtsstudierenden regulär zu Beginn ihres Masterstudiums in drei ihrer Studienfächer bzw. Förderschwerpunkte auf das Praxissemester vorbereitet. Die betreffenden Seminare sind inhaltlich unabhängig voneinander aus Perspektive der betreffenden Disziplinen heraus konzipiert. Im Praxissemester selbst führen die Studierenden dann nur in einem Fach, der so genannten Profilgruppe, ein universitärbegleitetes Studienprojekt durch und müssen sich also z.B. zwischen ihrem Förderschwerpunkt und ihrem Fach entscheiden. Vor dem Hintergrund von Inklusion und der im Kontext aufgeworfenen Forschungsdesiderata entwickeln, erproben und erforschen wir (Falkenstörfer, Keeley &amp;amp; Zepter) derzeit ein neues Studienprojekt-Format. Im WS 2016/2017 startete das Kooperationsprojekt zwischen dem Fach Deutsch und dem Förderschwerpunkt Geistige Entwicklung mit einem ersten Piloten. In dem neuen Format erarbeiten die Studierenden in einer „Zwei-Disziplinen-Profilgruppe“ ein interdisziplinäres Studienprojekt. Ein konzeptionelles Prinzip bildet die ausschließlich gemeinsame Betreuung: Alle Betreuungskomponenten werden von zwei Dozentinnen, jeweils eine aus den beiden Disziplinen, zusammen ausgerichtet. Das Projekt stellt auch an sich ein interdisziplinäres Forschungsprojekt dar, das bei den zwei Forschungsfragen ansetzt, wie (a) Theorien und empirische Erkenntnisse aus Fach und Förderschwerpunkt zueinander in Bezug gesetzt werden können und wie sich (b) interdisziplinäres Denken im Rahmen der „Zwei-Disziplinen-Profilgruppe“ entfalten kann. Ziel ist es, den Studierenden die forschungsbezogene Kooperation der beiden Disziplinen und derart interdisziplinäres Denken exemplarisch bzw. unterstützend aufzuzeigen, um sie dazu zu befähigen, unterrichtsbezogene Fragestellungen (disziplinenübergreifend) metatheoretisch reflektiert bzw. wo nötig interdisziplinär zu bearbeiten. Unsere These ist dabei, dass interdisziplinäres Denken zugleich ein Ziel und ein Mittel für Reflexivität in der Lehrer*innenbildung konstituiert.</dc:description>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en-US">
It is a key component of the internship-model of the University of&amp;nbsp; Cologne that at the beginning of any teaching degree master program, all students get prepared in three of their subjects of study in parallel seminars planned separately by each discipline. During the internship, the students work on a research assignment in only one discipline, the so-called “Zwei-Disziplinen-Profilgruppe” [“two disciplines profile group”]. Taking into account the topic of inclusion and corresponding research demands, we are currently developing a new format of the assignment in a cooperation between the disciplines “German Studies” and “Education and Rehabilitation of Students with (Profound) Intellectual and Multiple Disabilities.” In the new format, implemented since fall semester 2016/17, the students plan and undertake an interdisciplinary research assignment in a "Zwei-Disziplinen-Profilgruppe” (group consisting of members from two disciplines). A key principle of the supervision is team teaching: all components are conducted by two instructors, one of each discipline. The cooperation is in itself an interdisciplinary research project, with the focus on two research questions: (a) how theories and empirical findings of the two disciplines can be brought together and related to one another; and (b) how interdisciplinary thinking can be developed in the context of the "Zwei-Disziplinen-Profilgruppe”. The aim is to ex emplarily introduce the students to the research cooperation in order to enable them to work on teaching-related questions in an interdisciplinary and theoretically reflected approach. In this respect, our claim is that interdisciplinary thinking is at the same time object of and means for reflexivity in the academic education of prospective teachers.
</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="de-DE">Bielefeld School of Education (BiSEd)</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2018-12-21</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.herausforderung-lehrerinnenbildung.de/index.php/hlz/article/view/2416</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/hlz-2416</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">Herausforderung Lehrer*innenbildung - Zeitschrift zur Konzeption, Gestaltung und Diskussion; Bd. 1 Nr. 2 (2018): Studienprojekte im Praxissemester; 211-227</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Challenge Teacher Education; Vol. 1 No. 2 (2018): Student projects during internships in teacher education; 211-227</dc:source>
      <dc:source>2625-0675</dc:source>
      <dc:language>deu</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.herausforderung-lehrerinnenbildung.de/index.php/hlz/article/view/2416/2412</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">Copyright (c) 2018 Sophia Falkenstörfer, Caren Keeley, Alexandra Lavinia Zepter</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
