<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/2441</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-05-25T10:05:04Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>hlz:E_GRH</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">Kooperation in universitären Querstrukturen: Eine qualitative Studie über die besonderen Herausforderungen der Lehramtsausbildung aus Sicht der Fachdidaktiken.: Eine qualitative Studie über die besonderen Herausforderungen der Lehramtsausbildung aus Sicht der Fachdidaktiken.</dc:title>
      <dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Cross-structural cooperation at universities: A qualitative study on the special challenges of teacher education from a didactic point of view</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Koevel, Arne</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Nerdinger, Friedemann W.</dc:creator>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Lehrerbildung</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Organisation</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">qualitative Interviewstudie</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Organisationsentwicklung</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Teacher Education</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Organization</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Qualitative Interview Study</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Organisational Development</dc:subject>
      <dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">Der vorliegende Beitrag untersucht die besonderen Herausforderungen der Kooperation zwischen den am universitären Lehramtsstudium Beteiligten aus Sicht der Fachdidaktiken. Das Kombinationsstudium liegt in einem Spannungsfeld unterschiedlicher Anforderungen, die von zahlreichen inner- und außeruniversitären Institutionen und Akteuren gestellt werden. In einer qualitativen Interviewstudie (N = 9) werden organisationale und strukturelle Hindernisse aus Sicht der Fachdidaktiken exploriert. Sie kommt zu drei zentralen Ergebnissen: (1) Sichtbarkeit und Interessenvertretung der Lehramtsausbildenden gegenüber Hochschulleitungen und Ministerium sind mangelhaft. (2) Es fehlt Durchsetzungsmacht gegenüber den flankierenden Fachwissenschaften. (3) Die Erfüllung der durch das Ministerium auferlegten Vorgaben wird durch dieses unzureichend unterstützt. Die Ergebnisse werden vor dem Hintergrund organisationstheoretischer Erkenntnisse diskutiert und Implikationen für die Hochschulpolitik abgeleitet.
Schlagworte:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Lehrerbildung, Organisation, qualitative Interviewstudie, Organisationsentwicklung</dc:description>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en-US">This article examines the specific challenges that occur in the process of cooperation between those involved in university teaching studies, while focusing on a didactic point of view. Teacher studies as an academic field faces complex influences by numerous institutional players. Different requirements set by these institutions are being explored systematically for their organizational and structural obstacles in a qualitative interview study (N = 9). This results in three main conclusions: (1) The interests and struggles of those involved in training aspiring teachers are neither being communicated and negotiated clearly enough towards university an government authorities nor seen or noted by those. (2) There is a strong tendency of scientific disciplines interfering didactics. (3) The fulfillment of the requirements imposed by the ministry is insufficiently supported by this. The results are discussed against the background of organizational theory and implications for university policy are derived.
Key Words:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Teacher Education, Organization, Qualitative Interview Study, Organisational</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="de-DE">Bielefeld School of Education (BiSEd)</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2019-07-10</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:type xml:lang="de-DE">Begutachteter Beitrag</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.herausforderung-lehrerinnenbildung.de/index.php/hlz/article/view/2441</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/hlz-2441</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">Herausforderung Lehrer*innenbildung - Zeitschrift zur Konzeption, Gestaltung und Diskussion; Bd. 2 Nr. 1 (2019): Herausforderung Lehrer_innenbildung - Ausgabe 2; 123-143</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Challenge Teacher Education; Vol. 2 No. 1 (2019): Challenge Teacher Education - Vol. 2; 123-143</dc:source>
      <dc:source>2625-0675</dc:source>
      <dc:language>deu</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.herausforderung-lehrerinnenbildung.de/index.php/hlz/article/view/2441/2443</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">Copyright (c) 2019 Arne Koevel, Friedemann W. Nerdinger</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
