<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>2464</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">Sprachlich inklusiv unterrichten lernen – Konzept und Wirksamkeit einer fachdidaktischen Lehrveranstaltung</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Learning to Teach Subject Matters in Language-Inclusive Ways – Approaches and Effects of a Didactic Pre-service Teacher Education Course</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Sahin-Gür, Dilan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Prediger, Susanne</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">inklusiver Fachunterricht</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Diversitätsaspekt</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Sprachkompetenz</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Seminarkonzept</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">sprachsensible Orientierungen</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Kategorien</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">empirische Evidenz für Wirksamkeit</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">inclusive subject  matter teaching</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">language diversity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">seminar program</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">language-responsive orientations</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">categories</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">empirical evidences for effectiveness</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">Präsentiert werden das Konzept, die Umsetzung und die Wirksamkeitsevaluation einer Master-Veranstaltung, in der Studierende lernen, sprachlich inklusiven Fachunterricht zu erteilen. Dazu werden im Seminar sprach- und fachdidaktische Hintergründe in situierten, reichhaltigen Lernsituationen erarbeitet und durch zunehmende Integration verknüpft. Die Wirksamkeit des Veranstaltungskonzepts wurde im Prä-Post-Design mit Kontrollgruppe evaluiert, und zwar im Hinblick auf Diagnosekategorien und Orientierungen der Studierenden zu sprachlich inklusivem Fachunterricht. Orientierungen der n = 52 Lehramtsstudierenden wurden durch standardisierte Skalen erhoben und die individuellen Kategorien in veranstaltungsintegrierten diagnostischen Aktivitäten. Der Gruppenvergleich der jeweiligen Veränderung von Vor- zu Nacherhebung zeigt in der Interventionsgruppe eine deutliche Verschiebung hin zu lernförderlicheren Orientierungen und zu einer breiteren und treffsichereren Aktivierung wichtiger Kategorien für die Diagnose.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">This article presents the approaches, realization and effectiveness study of a Master course in which pre-service mathematics teachers learn to teach language-inclusive subject matter classrooms. The Master course develops language- and subject-specific pedagogical content knowledge in rich situated learning environments and increasingly integrates both knowledge areas. The effectiveness of the course is evaluated in a quasi-randomized controlled trial with a control group, with respect to pre-service teachers’ diagnostic categories and language-responsive orientations. The orientations of the n = 52 pre-service teachers are assessed by standardized scales, the individual categories in situated diagnostic activities. The comparison of changes in the intervention and control group from the pre-test to the post-test shows a clear shift in the intervention group towards more productive orientations and a broader and more accurate activation of diagnostic categories.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="de-DE">Bielefeld School of Education (BiSEd)</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="de-DE">Begutachteter Beitrag</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.herausforderung-lehrerinnenbildung.de/index.php/hlz/article/view/2464</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/hlz-2464</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">Herausforderung Lehrer*innenbildung - Zeitschrift zur Konzeption, Gestaltung und Diskussion; Bd. 2 Nr. 3 (2019): Lehrerinnen- und Lehrerbildung für die inklusive Schule - Fachdidaktische und bildungswissenschaftliche Ansätze; 193-213</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Challenge Teacher Education; Vol. 2 No. 3 (2019): Approaches to Teacher Education for Inclusive Schools; 193-213</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2625-0675</dc:source>
	<dc:language>deu</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.herausforderung-lehrerinnenbildung.de/index.php/hlz/article/view/2464/3231</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">Copyright (c) 2019 Dilan Sahin-Gür, Susann Prediger</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>