<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/4045</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-09-20T13:01:23Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>hlz:L2_KG</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">Perspektiven von Schüler*innen auf das „Rausgehen“ als gemeinsamer Reflexionsimpuls: Lehrkonzeption für eine digitale (lehramtsübergreifende) Fallarbeit</dc:title>
      <dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Secondary-School Students’ Views on Pull-out as an Opportunity for Reflective Practices in Inclusive Teacher Education: A Cased-Based Approach within a (Collaborative) Online Learning Format</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Arndt, Ann-Kathrin</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Becker, Jonas</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Köhler, Sina-Mareen</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Löser, Jessica M.</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Urban, Michael</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Werning, Rolf</dc:creator>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Inklusive Lehrer*innenbildung</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Kasuistik</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Schüler*innensichtweisen</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">äußere Differenzierung</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Kooperation</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Online-Lehre</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">inclusive teacher education</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">cased-based learning</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">secondary-school student’s view</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">pull-out</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">collaboration</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">online learning</dc:subject>
      <dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">In dem Beitrag wird eine Lehrkonzeption für eine digitale (lehramtsübergreifende) Fallarbeit vorgeschlagen. Diese umfasst zwei Sitzungen und wurde im digitalen Sommersemester 2020 zum einen an den Standorten Aachen und Hannover „lehramtsübergreifend“ mit Studierenden der Sonderpädagogik sowie des Lehramts an Gymnasien und Gesamtschulen bzw. des Lehramts an Berufskollegs, zum anderen am Standort Göttingen im gymnasialen Lehramt erprobt. Die Konzeption umfasst eine individuelle Auseinandersetzung mit kasuistischem Material sowie daran anschließend einen digitalen Austausch in Studierendengruppen mittels Videokonferenz. Auf Basis von qualitativ-empirischen Ergebnissen rückt das Phänomen „Rausgehen“ im Sinne einer leistungsbezogenen äußeren Differenzierung im Kontext des Förderschwerpunktes Lernen in den Fokus. Hierbei wird an ein Verständnis von Schule als Ort der (Re-)Produktion von Differenz angeschlossen. Der Schwerpunkt der Fallarbeit liegt auf Perspektiven von Schüler*innen. Hierbei geht es sowohl um das eigene Rausgehen als auch das Rausgehen anderer. Die Lehrkonzeption zielt darauf, den Studierenden die Reflexion von Differenzkonstruktionen im schulischen Kontext zu ermöglichen. In der Konzeption der Fallarbeit werden u.a. Strategien der Grounded Theory aufgegriffen, jedoch erfolgt keine im engeren Sinne forschungsmethodische Ausrichtung. Ausgehend von gängigen Systematisierungen kasuistischer Ansätze, die u.a. zwischen forschungsorientiert/rekonstruktiv und praxisreflexiv/-analytisch unterscheiden, kann dies als „Mischform“ gefasst werden. Das fokussierte Phänomen Rausgehen greift (multi-)professionelle Kooperation als Thema inklusiver Lehrer*innenbildung auf; in der lehramtsübergreifenden Variante spiegelt sich diese zudem im Format wider. In dem Beitrag werden Ablauf und Materialien sowie studentische Rückmeldungen zur digitalen (lehramtsübergreifenden) Fallarbeit vorgestellt.</dc:description>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en-US">In this paper we present a concept as well as case materials for a digital (collaborative) case-based approach within pre-service inclusive teacher education. Based on the BMBF funded project ReLInk, this was developed following the changeover to online teaching and learning in summer semester 2020. This online cased-based learning approach was carried out within a collaborative format between special and general education courses of the universities of Aachen and Hanover as well as within an advanced secondary education course at Göttingen university. In the first week, students engaged with case materials individually. Based on this, online meetings in small groups took place in the following week. Drawing on empirical results of the project ReLInk the case-based learning focuses on secondary students’ views on pull-out situations in the context of ability grouping linked to special education need categorization. In accordance to previous research, we refer to an understanding which emphasizes the role of school in (re)producing difference. With our cased-based learning we aim to encourage reflective practices in pre-service teacher education which address the construction of difference in schools. While our concept for cased-based learning is inspired by Grounded Theory, we do not concentrate on research methods or research-oriented learning. By thus, our concept can be regarded as a mixed-form with respect to given distinctions between cased-based learning formats. By focusing on pull-out, we join current attempts to increase considerations of (inter-)professional collaboration within pre-service teacher-training. In our paper, we present materials, tasks and impulses as well as students’ feedback.</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="de-DE">Bielefeld School of Education (BiSEd)</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2021-06-29</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.herausforderung-lehrerinnenbildung.de/index.php/hlz/article/view/4045</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.11576/hlz-4045</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">Herausforderung Lehrer*innenbildung - Zeitschrift zur Konzeption, Gestaltung und Diskussion; Bd. 4 Nr. 1 (2021): Herausforderung Lehrer*innenbildung - Ausgabe 4; 135-157</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Challenge Teacher Education; Vol. 4 No. 1 (2021): Herausforderung Lehrer*innenbildung - Ausgabe 4; 135-157</dc:source>
      <dc:source>2625-0675</dc:source>
      <dc:language>deu</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.herausforderung-lehrerinnenbildung.de/index.php/hlz/article/view/4045/4345</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>https://www.herausforderung-lehrerinnenbildung.de/index.php/hlz/article/view/4045/4346</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>https://www.herausforderung-lehrerinnenbildung.de/index.php/hlz/article/view/4045/4347</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">Copyright (c) 2021 Ann-Kathrin Arndt, Jonas Becker, Sina-Mareen Köhler, Jessica M. Löser, Michael Urban, Rolf Werning</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
