<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>1101</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Archaeology goes to high school : Practical approach to archaeology teaching in high school</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Vijand, Liia</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Purpose: The study investigated how various school subjects can be integrated into archaeology teaching and how this could lead students towards empathy and a more sustainable worldview. Design/methodology/approach: To meet the purpose of this multiple-case study, optional archaeology course development (2011-2019) and students’ questionnaires and feedback group A (2018) and group B (2019) and various empirical material, was analysed in cross-case methods. Findings: Archaeology interdisciplinarity and analysing long-term human behaviour supports an understanding of human nature, emphasizes empathy and tolerance, and encourages social cohesion.Research limitations/implications: The study was carried out in Estonia as a multiple-case study and further research, especially in the empathy part, is needed for further conclusions. Practical implications: Archaeology is interdisciplinary and therefore as a school subject it links together various and sometimes abstract subjects. It gives an understanding of long-term human behaviour, which allows developing students’ empathy and tolerance.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-12-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/1101</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-1101</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Bd. 18 Nr. 4 (2019):  Participation in Non-Formal Education and Community Education - Implications for Civic and Political Capital; 102-122</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Vol. 18 No. 4 (2019):  Participation in Non-Formal Education and Community Education - Implications for Civic and Political Capital; 102-122</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/1101/3306</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2019 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>