<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/1243</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-11-15T18:21:17Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>jsse:ART</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Preparing to Teach Democracy: Student Teachers’ Perceptions of the ‘Democracy Cake’ as a Set of Teaching Materials in Social Science Education</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Mathé, Nora Elise Hesby</dc:creator>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Social studies, teacher education, didactics, democracy, teaching materials</dc:subject>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Purpose: Few studies have examined student teachers’ perceptions of teaching&amp;nbsp;materials on democracy. For the purpose of addressing how teacher education in social&amp;nbsp;science might contribute to student teachers’ qualifications for teaching democracy, this&amp;nbsp;study investigated student teachers’ perceptions of the ‘Democracy Cake’ as a set of&amp;nbsp;teaching materials for teaching democracy in social science education.
Design/methodology/approach: This study relied on a survey and observations among&amp;nbsp;47 student teachers in a social science didactics course.
Findings: Analyses of student teachers’ perceptions revealed concerns about teaching&amp;nbsp;social science concepts, engagement of secondary school students in classroom&amp;nbsp;discussions and the theoretical framing of the teaching materials.
Research limitations: The study focused on 47 student teachers’ perceptions of a&amp;nbsp;particular set of teaching materials and may not be generalisable.
Practical implications: This study indicates that social science teacher education might&amp;nbsp;benefit from involving student teachers in the examination of teaching materials.</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2020-03-27</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Text</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/1243</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-1243</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Bd. 19 Nr. 3 (2020): Open topics</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Vol. 19 No. 3 (2020): Open topics</dc:source>
      <dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/1243/3906</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2020 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
