<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/1514</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-07-01T09:58:58Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>jsse:FeT</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Funding community education in Ireland: Making the case for a needs-based approach</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Magrath, Conor Joseph</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Fitzsimons, Camilla</dc:creator>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Purpose: This report captures the experiences of 56 participating community education organisations across Ireland and aims to uncover trends and issues in funding models.
Design/methodology/approach: A mixed-methods research was undertaken in three phases. Phase one involved an online- survey, which asked about primary and secondary sources of funding, ease of administration, access and sustainability. Phase two consisted of one-to-one interviews with self-selected providers and in phase three, we returned to the participants of phase two with targeted questions specifically relating to the pressures to merge with non-independent, state providers of community education.
Findings: A disconnect between funders and providers, has been highlighted. Particularly the outcomes based funding model, which prioritises jobs activation over social inclusion. Funding is seen as restrictive, anti-innovative, bureaucratic and non-transparent.
Practical implications: A need for sustainable, multi-annual funding has been identified, with providers looking for greater acknowledgement and recognition of the vital role and true value of community education in Irish society.</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2019-05-20</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:type xml:lang="en-US">text</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/1514</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-1514</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Bd. 18 Nr. 4 (2019):  Participation in Non-Formal Education and Community Education - Implications for Civic and Political Capital; 38-50</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Vol. 18 No. 4 (2019):  Participation in Non-Formal Education and Community Education - Implications for Civic and Political Capital; 38-50</dc:source>
      <dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/1514/3408</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2019 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
