<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>305</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">What Would You Decide on? Decision Tasks in Economic Classes at Business Schools – A Didactical Analysis with Regard to Self-Directed Learning (in German)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Goeckede, Britta </dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">Presently, self-directed learning is an important demand in the educational and didactical discourse. Implementing tasks in class is a way to involve students actively. This article discusses the question to what extent two selected exemplary tasks used in economic classes enable learners to self-direct their solution-finding-process. The special nature of both tasks only allows solutions in the form of economic decisions, which means that the solution-finding-process is a decision-making-process. This investigation discusses what a complete and ideal decision-making-process proves to be. This knowledge will then provide a basis for evaluating the tasks in terms of to what extent the learners perform this decision-making-process while they are working on it. Finally, the so called "decision tasks" are analyzed on the criteria of complexity and openness to make a statement about the impact of internal and external control. In the framework of this text analysis, we arrive at the conclusion that the tasks taken into consideration allow self-directed processing only in small parts, but an opening seems to be possible while they are being used in class.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2004-08-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/305</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-305</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 2-2004: Constructivism</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 2-2004: Constructivism</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
	<dc:language>deu</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/305/302</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-305</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2004 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>