<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/3273</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-07-01T09:58:58Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>jsse:CRP</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="de-DE"> : Past and present of social science education in Hungary</dc:title>
      <dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Hungary:: Past and present of social science education in Hungary</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Dancs, Katinka</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Fülöp, Márta</dc:creator>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Purpose: We intent to provide a comprehensive picture of Hungarian social science education, to review the constituents of social science literacy, a systematic analysis of the curriculum and its changes since 1989 and of the available research in this field.
Design/methodology/approach: The findings are based on the analysis of educational documents (e. g. curricula) and the review of the research publications in the field.
Findings: Social science education is cross-curricular in Hungary. Among the different knowledge fields history has a decisive and dominant role. Other social science topics are mostly abandoned in everyday teaching practice. There is a growing centralization of the educational arena (e.g. government approved limited number of textbooks) and a growing emphasis on national identity and patriotism and a decreasing emphasis on Europe. The cross-curricular nature of social science education would require well trained teachers who are able to think critically and in a complex way themselves, however teacher training and classroom practice also support the hegemony of history teaching. </dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2020-01-16</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/3273</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-3273</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Bd. 19 Nr. 1 (2020): Outlining Similarities and Differences in Civics Education in Europe</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Vol. 19 No. 1 (2020): Outlining Similarities and Differences in Civics Education in Europe</dc:source>
      <dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/3273/3544</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2020 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
