<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/3466</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-12-20T09:07:08Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>jsse:SART</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Researching global citizenship education: Towards a critical approach</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Schippling, Anne</dc:creator>
      <dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">global citizenship education, transnational capital, methodological nationalism, international school, biographical case study</dc:subject>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Purpose: This article contains a reflection on researching in global citizenship education with a critical approach that aims to transcend the paradigm of methodological nationalism.
Design/methodology/approach: Starting from outlining different dimensions of global citizenship (education), and looking at the current research situation in GCE, we propose a methodological turn that overcomes the nation-state paradigm as a base for critical research on GCE. Subsequently, using the concept of transnational capital as an analytical tool, we show – in the example of two biographical case studies in an international school in a large city of West Germany – how to put a critical research on GCE into action.
Findings: The article demonstrates, on the one hand, how a critical approach to research aspects of global citizenship education can be taken, starting from a transnational research stance. On the other hand, it presents new perspectives and challenges for critical research in GCE.</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2020-12-18</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:type xml:lang="en-US">text</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/3466</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-3466</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Bd. 19 Nr. 4 (2020): Global education at crossroads</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Vol. 19 No. 4 (2020): Global education at crossroads</dc:source>
      <dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/3466/4001</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2020 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
