<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>3467</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Critical and Postcolonial Perspectives on Global Education: The Case of Poland</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Kuleta-Hulboj, Magdalena</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">global education, postcolonial pedagogy, Poland, semi-peripheral country, double coloniality</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Purpose: This paper aims to contribute to the academic debate on postcolonial perspectives on global education problematising the context of global education in Poland, a former Second World country that does not fit to Global North-Global South dichotomy.
Approach: The article explores global education in Poland from a critical and postcolonial perspective. It examines both supra-national factors shaping global education nowadays (like migrations, cosmopolitan turn, growing right-wing populism, the culture of measurement) and specific Polish context as a country not only “in-between”, but with the experience of “triple coloniality”.
Findings: I argue that taking into consideration this complexity and multilayeredness of the Polish situation, together with more general, not country-specific factors, can offer new insights and understandings of global education in Poland. It is a necessary step to decolonise global education and make it more inclusive.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">text</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/3467</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-3467</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Bd. 19 Nr. 4 (2020): Global education at crossroads</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Vol. 19 No. 4 (2020): Global education at crossroads</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/3467/3994</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2020 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>