<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>3960</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Consumer education as counselling? Teacher beliefs about consumption and (social science) education</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Wittau, Franziska</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">economic education</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">social studies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">consumer education</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">teacher professionalism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">teacher training</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">- Consumer education is a normative field of action.
- Social science teachers base the design of consumer education concepts often on their own, milieu-bound values.
- Especially when teachers see students' consumption as deficient, consumer education has the task to teach appropriate consumption patterns.
- In formal teacher training processes, students’ everyday experiences as members of society can serve as a starting point for self-reflective processes.
Purpose: This article aims to discuss the influence of milieu-based daily life experiences on teaching social science studies by taking the example of consumption. It should be asked to what extent personal habitus in a Bourdieuian sense influences teachers’ beliefs about consumer education in particular and social science education in general. 
Method: Qualitative interviews and group discussions with 19 teachers out of the social science domain were analysed following the concept of interpretation patterns as socially shared world views. 
Findings: Personal experiences and common knowledge based on the daily involvement in consumption practices are a crucial factor influencing consumer education. They lead rather to tendencies of overwhelming students than imparting knowledge about consumption as a social phenomenon. Implications: Teacher training in fields of social science education, which is strongly related milieu-driven daily life, should focus a distanced, reflective and multiperspective view on the teaching practices based on professional, theoretic knowledge.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-10-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">text</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/3960</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11576/jsse-3960</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Bd. 20 Nr. 3 (2021): Teacher training</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Vol. 20 No. 3 (2021): Teacher training</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/3960/4514</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>