<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>4452</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Visual ethnography in classrooms: the “action of showing” in classroom videos in contexts of social science teacher education</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Jehle, May</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">visual ethnography</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">classroom videography</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">social science teacher education</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">German reunification and process of transformation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">teaching practices</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">
Unique historical sources of German social science classroom videos in the phase of 1990–91
Historical documentation of the relations between camerawork and intentions for further use
Insights into documentary practices and implicit images of teaching methods and practices
Reconstruction of the complex and multi-layered process of image production
Classroom videography needs a reflection of the complex process of meaningful image production

Purpose: The paper discusses the camerawork within a historic video case study as a meaningful practice of visualization of classrooms and also as an aspect worth consideration in current contexts of video-based classroom research and teacher education.
Design/methodology/approach: The case study combines elements of video hermeneutics and a visual sociology of knowledge to reconstruct the visual within historic classroom videos. It discusses these reconstructions based on the theoretical framework of video ethnography as an alternative method of classroom research focused on specific actions of showing within the historical context.
Findings: The analysis and interpretation underpin the assumption of relations between camerawork and intentions for the use of the videos and enables insights into practices of documentation, implicit images of teaching practices, and classroom interaction as a part of the history of social science education.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-01-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Text</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/4452</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11576/jsse-4452</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Bd. 20 Nr. 4 (2021): Classroom ethnography and rituals in schools</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Vol. 20 No. 4 (2021): Classroom ethnography and rituals in schools</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/4452/4692</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2022 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>