<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>4468</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Contractualism as an element of democratic pedagogy?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Budde, Jürgen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Hellberg, Lotta</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Weuster, Nora</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Contractual pedagogy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">ethnography</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">education</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">theory of practice</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">subjectivation</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">
Pedagogical practices are based on establishing commitment.
Contractual pedagogy corresponds to a contract-based social order.
Contractual pedagogy aims at democratizing pedagogical relationships.
Contractual pedagogy involves a pedagogic process of collective subjectivation.
Contractual pedagogy does not represent the kind of pedagogical ‘counter-model’ familiar to progressive pedagogies that aspire towards democratic codetermination.

Purpose: This article investigates the establishment of commitment in pedagogical practices through what are known as ‘behavioural contracts’. Such contracts are seen as a participatory element of democratic pedagogy and are linked to the aim of strengthening students’ self-determination. The objective is to demonstrate that as a pedagogical phenomenon, contractual pedagogy is oriented towards a practice of self-control achieved through external control, assuming a basis of sovereignty and reason.
Methodology: The article provides an investigation of material from an ethnographic research project in Germany on social learning in school-based pedagogical contexts. The study is informed by practice theory, theory of school and theory of social pedagogics.
Findings: This article argues that contractual pedagogy as a subjectivising constellation is primarily directed towards re-establishing the pre-existing institutional order. It demonstrates that contractual pedagogy can neither be understood as a particularly participatory method of democratic pedagogy, nor as a governmental power strategy, but as a subjectivising exercise that introduces students to a central tenet in modern societies. Through this, connections are formed between specific forms of (collective) subjectivation.
Research implications: Further theoretical and empirical analyses are required, which make other pedagogical impulses, such as an ethics of care or the critique of the subject, fruitful for Democratic Pedagogy.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-01-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">text</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/4468</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11576/jsse-4468</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Bd. 20 Nr. 4 (2021): Classroom ethnography and rituals in schools</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Vol. 20 No. 4 (2021): Classroom ethnography and rituals in schools</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/4468/4691</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2022 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>