<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/503</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-05-25T11:54:40Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>jsse:CRP</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">Norwegian Civic Education – Beyond Formalism?</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Børhaug, Kjetil </dc:creator>
      <dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">Norwegian civic education traces its origin almost 200 years back in time. Until World War II, its main focus was on constitutional matters and on the formal structure of governmental institutions. After 1945, and in particular after the 1970s, conceptions of civic education change. Among others, critical perspectives, political participation and democratic ideals became major issues. Have these ideas been able to influence teaching practices?L’éducation civique norvégienne s’est développée depuis presque 200 ans. Jusqu’à la seconde guerre mondiale, le contenu principal portait sur la constitution et la structure formelle des institutions politiques de l’état. Après la guerre, et surtout après 1970, jaillirent de nouvelles idées plus radicales sur l’éducation civique changeant le cadre de l’enseignement. Ces idées amenèrent une reformulation des objectifs fondamentaux basés sur des perspectives critiques, une participation politique plus importante et les idéaux démocratiques. Mais ces idées, ont-elles influencé l’enseignement de cette matière dans les écoles norvégiennes?</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2010-07-12</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/503</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-503</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 1-2010: Civic and Economic Education and the Current Financial Crisis I</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 1-2010: Civic and Economic Education and the Current Financial Crisis I</dc:source>
      <dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/503/500</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-503</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2010 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
