<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>539</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">The Epistemological and Didactical Challenges Involved in Teaching Socially Acute Questions. The Example of Globalization</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Simonneaux, Jean </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Legardez, Alain </dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">Teachers are being asked to manage a specific didactic situation which falls into the category of what we have proposed to call “socially acute questions (SAQs)”. A SAQ is a question which is acute in society, in background knowledge and in knowledge taught. Thus, teaching SAQs demands socio-epistemological reflexivity in the processes of knowledge production and in the social conditions in which this knowledge emerges; teaching SAQs will give priority to interdisciplinary, scientific and ethical reasoning. The split between ideology and science can certainly be examined when considering a socially acute question which is the subject of debate in society. In the example of the globalization taught: the diversity of analysis in the economic domain gives rise to great uncertainty because it justifies practically opposing policies; within a transdisciplinary framework, the globalization includes concepts, ideologies or social practices in a double movement of standardization and differentiation. By way of SAQs, we have attempted to show that learning stakes are numerous. However didactic choices must be supported by socio-epistemological survey, the identification of an epistemological posture and the definition of a didactic strategyLes enseignants sont appelés à gérer une situation didactique spécifique dans l’enseignement des «questions socialement vives (QSV) ». Les QSV sont des questions qui donnent lieu à débat dans la société, dans les savoirs scientifiques et dans l’enseignement. Ainsi, l‘enseignement des QSV nécessite une réflexivité socio-épistémologique dans le processus de production du savoir et dans les conditions sociales d’émergence de ces savoirs; l’enseignement des QSV donnera la priorité au raisonnement interdisciplinaire, scientifique et éthique. La scission entre l‘idéologie et la science peut être examinée lors de l‘examen d‘une QSV qui fait l‘objet d‘un débat dans la société. Dans l‘exemple de l’enseignement de la mondialisation: la diversité des analyses économiques donne lieu à une grande incertitude en justifiant des politiques quasi-opposées; dans un cadre transdisciplinaire, la mondialisation recouvre des concepts, des idéologies ou des pratiques sociales dans un double mouvement d‘uniformisation et de différenciation. Nous avons tenté de montrer que les enjeux de l‘apprentissage sont nombreux dans les l’enseignement des QSV. Les choix didactiques doivent être soutenues par une enquête socio-épistémologique, l‘identification d’une posture épistémologique et la définition d‘une stratégie didactique.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2010-12-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/539</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-539</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 4-2010: Social Science Literacy I: In Search for Basic Competences and Basic Concepts for Testing and Diagnosing Political and Economic Literacy</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 4-2010: Social Science Literacy I: In Search for Basic Competences and Basic Concepts for Testing and Diagnosing</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/539/536</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-539</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2010 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>