<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/563</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-05-25T11:52:40Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>jsse:ART</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">“This is how you do it in Germany, but we do it our way.” Different Notions of Citizenship Education in the Russian-German Exchange of Young Professionals</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Busuleanu, Štepánka </dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ivanova-Chessex, Oxana </dc:creator>
      <dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">Citizenship education is a widespread concept of lifelong learning important for democratic participation. The research shows a great variety in approaches to citizenship education depending on socio-political contexts (Bîrzéa 2004, 17; Kerr, Nelson 2005, 10). This study is based on participative evaluation (Bergold 2007; Cousins, Earl 1992) accompanying the German-Russian training and exchange program regarding non-formal citizenship education. Through content analysis of interviews and artifacts we explore views of citizenship education and strategies that the actors use to deal with the various assumptions in this field of education. In Germany democracy, participation and critical thinking are emphasized, in contrast to Russia, where, depending on the organizational structure, the patriotic upbringing is exercised. Four ways of dealing with the conflicting assumptions and practices are identified in the issue-focused exchange of young professionals. They are the individual construction of the German and Russian ways of citizenship education, enrichment of individual understanding, reduction of the perceived differences and conformity with ones environment juggling with declared and practiced notionsCitizenship education ist ein verbreitetes Konzept des lebenslangen Lernens mit dem Ziel, demokratisch orientierte Partizipation zu fördern. Laut Forschung variieren die Ansätze von citizenship education in Abhängigkeit vom soziopolitischen Kontext (Bîrzéa 2004: 17; Kerr/ Nelson 2005: 10). Die vorliegende Untersuchung basiert auf einer partizipativen Evaluation (Bergold 2007; Cousins/ Earl 1992), die im deutsch-russischen Fachkräfteaustausch zum Thema citizenship education durchgeführt wurde. Durch die qualitative Inhaltsanalyse von Interviews und Artefakten werden die Auffassungen der Akteure von citizenship education untersucht und ihre Strategien im Umgang mit differierenden Annahmen rekonstruiert. Die Befunde zeigen: Die deutsche Befragtengruppe betont Demokratie, Partizipation und kritisches Denken, während in vielen russischen Organisationen (abhängig von strukturellen Rahmenbedingungen) eine patriotische Erziehung praktiziert wird. Vier Wege im Umgang mit widersprüchlichen Auffassungen und Praktiken werden im Rahmen der untersuchten themenorientierten Austauschmaßnahme eruiert. Diese sind die Konstruktion eines deutschen und russischen Ansatzes von citizenship education, die Entwicklung eines individuellen Verständnisses, die Reduktion der wahrgenommenen Differenzen sowie die Anpassung an das Umfeld, bei der deklarierte und handlungsrelevante Annahmen einander widersprechen können.</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2011-06-10</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/563</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-563</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 2-2011: Praise of Difference: Dealing with Heterogeneity in Socio-Scientific Education</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 2-2011: Praise of Difference: Dealing with Heterogeneity in Socio-Scientific Education</dc:source>
      <dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/563/560</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-563</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2011 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
