<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>565</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">Heterogene Schülerkonzepte für ökonomische Phänomene: ihre Erfassung und Konsequenzen für den Unterricht (Students’ Heterogeneous Concepts of Economic Phenomena: How to Ascertain These and Consequences in the Classroom)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Birke, Franziska </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Seeber, Günther </dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">Der vorliegende Beitrag widmet sich der Erfassung heterogenen Verständnisses von ökonomischen Phänomenen bei Schülerinnen und Schülern. Die Autoren gehen davon aus, dass ein besseres Verständnis dieser Heterogenität für die Wirtschaftsdidaktik in Wissenschaft und Praxis von fundamentaler Bedeutung ist. Da mit der Phänomenographie ein geeignetes Erfassungsinstrument zur Verfügung steht, das in der sozialwissenschaftlichen Didaktik des deutschsprachigen Raums bisher nahezu keine Rolle spielt, versprechen sie sich gerade hier neue Impulse. Der Artikel beschreibt und diskutiert ein phänomenographisches Vorgehen für die ökonomische Bildung in Abgrenzung zu anderen Methoden. Er schließt mit Implikationen für die Unterrichtspraxis, da eine Kombination der Phänomenographie mit einer Konzeptvariation die Schülerwahrnehmungen in den Wirtschaftsunterricht integrieren lässt und hilft, Lernfortschritte zu erzielenThis article addresses the issue of identifying students’ heterogeneous understanding of economic phenomena. The authors assume that a better understanding of this heterogeneity is essential for economic education in science and practice. Phenomenography stands by as an adequate tool for identifying heterogeneity. However, so far, it is hardly adapted in German-speaking social science didactics and therefore we hope for new stimuli from its reception. The article describes and discusses the phenomenographic approach in economic education in distinction to other available methods. It closes by showing the implications for lesson practice, because a combination of phenomenography and concept variation will help to integrate students’ perceptions into economic instruction and to achieve progress in learning.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2011-06-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/565</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-565</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 2-2011: Praise of Difference: Dealing with Heterogeneity in Socio-Scientific Education</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 2-2011: Praise of Difference: Dealing with Heterogeneity in Socio-Scientific Education</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
	<dc:language>deu</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/565/562</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-565</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2011 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>