<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/576</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-05-25T11:52:14Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>jsse:ART</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">Unpolite Citizenship: The Non-Place of Conflict in Political Education</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Monteiro, Hugo </dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Ferreira, Pedro Daniel </dc:creator>
      <dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">This paper considers the role of conflict (its constitutive relevance or erasure) in the concepts and practices of democracy and citizenship. Critically reflecting on contexts of formal and non-formal political education, and on the observed practices and discourse of relevant educational actors, we intend to interrogate the school’s conceptions, misconceptions and/or contradictions around democracy and political participation. Focusing on the arguments surrounding the perspectives oriented towards consensus vs. those embracing dissensus in social and political theories, this article considers the implicit and explicit powers existent or generated in school relationships, which inevitably affect our ways of looking at citizenship and of educating politicallyCet article prétend aborder le rôle du conflit (du point de vue de sa pertinence constitutive ou de son effacement) dans des conceptions et des pratiques de la démocratie ou citoyenneté. Sur la base d’une réflexion critique touchant aux concepts d’éducation politique formelle ou non-formelle, ainsi qu’aux pratiques et discours d’agents centraux de l’action éducationnelle qui ont pu être observés, nous prétendons identifier des concepts, malentendus et/ou contradictions ayant trait aux concepts de démocratie et de participation politique. En examinant les perspectives visant à atteindre un consensus opposées à l’ampleur des divergences au coeur des théories politiques et sociales, cet article se focalise sur des pouvoirs implicites ou explicites, présentifiés ou générés dans des relations scolaires, qui affectent inévitablement notre manière d’envisager la citoyenneté, ainsi que l’action d’éduquer politiquement.</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2011-12-20</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/576</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-576</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 4-2011: Critical Civic &amp; Citizenship Education</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 4-2011: Critical Civic &amp; Citizenship Education</dc:source>
      <dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/576/573</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-576</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2011 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
