<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>650</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">How can Economics Education be Implemented without a Separate Subject? A Case Study from Germany</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Weyland, Michael</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Rehm, Marco</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">The discussion about the pros and cons of economics as a school subject has been going on for many years – and agreement has still not been reached. It is therefore useful to set aside the debate about economics as a school subject for now and to address the question of how social science-based economics education in mainstream schools can be designed in such a way to be successful. During the 2012 conference of the Association of European Economics Education (AEEE), approximately 100 teachers, teacher trainers, inspectors and researchers with a professional interest in economics and business education from all over Europe visited a German grammar school with a focus on economics education. The Siebengebirgsgymnasium in Bad Honnef strives to provide all pupils with a basic economics education and a selection of additional social science-oriented classes. Using some exemplary projects it has been demonstrated how, since 2003, the Siebengebirgsgymnasium has been dedicated to constructively addressing the Kaminski-Hedtke controversy about politics and economics education and to fostering a creative and social science-based economics education.Die Diskussion über die Vor- und Nachteile eines Schulfachs Wirtschaft wird seit vielen Jahren geführt – und eine Einigung ist nicht in Sicht. Es erscheint daher sinnvoll, die Debatte über das Für und Wider eines Schulfachs Wirtschaft vorerst auszublenden und sich gemeinsam der Frage zuzuwenden, wie eine sozialwissenschaftlich fundierte ökonomische Bildung an allgemeinbildenden Schulen konkret ausgestaltet werden kann, damit sie erfolgreich ist. Im Rahmen der internationalen Tagung der Association of European Economics Education (AEEE) 2012 besuchten etwa 100 Lehrer, Seminarleiter, Inspektoren und Wissenschaftler aus ganz Europa eine allgemeinbildende deutsche Schule mit einem ökonomischem Profil. Das Städtische Siebengebirgsgymnasium hat es sich zum Ziel gesetzt, allen Schülerinnen und Schülern eine ökonomische Grundbildung zu vermitteln, um sie auf ein eigenverantwortliches Leben in einer zunehmend komplexen Gesellschaft vorzubereiten.. Anhand einiger exemplarischer Projekte wird aufgezeigt, wie diese Schule seit 2003 versucht, die Kaminski-Hedtke-Kontroverse kreativ zu wenden und eine sozialwissenschaftlich fundierte ökonomische Bildung zu realisieren.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2012-10-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
	<dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
	<dc:format>application/zip</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/650</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-650</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 2-2013: Crisis and Economic Education in Europe</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 2-2013: Crisis and Economic Education in Europe</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/650/677</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/650/678</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/650/679</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/650/680</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-650</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-650</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-650</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-650</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2013 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>