<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>669</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Civic Education and Democratic Socialisation: From Passive Subject to Active Citizen in Post-Communist States and Beyond</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Bruen, Jennifer</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Several studies suggest that some post-communist states or regions such as, for example, the former German Democratic Republic engage in a narrower form of civic education in schools which focuses on the transmission of facts. They also indicate that such civic education produces citizens more likely to accept the status quo than to criticially analyse and attempt to transform it. This paper posits, however, that this is also the case in the Republic of Ireland, a state with an apparently very different historical background. Attitudinal data from the European/World Values Survey and the European Social Survey is used to investigate this possibility by comparing eastern Germany and the Republic of Ireland on key items relating to attitudes towards politics and society. The results provide tentative support for this notion indicating that attitudes in both eastern Germany and the Republic of Ireland tend towards the compliance end of the compliancetransformation spectrum underlining the importance of broader forms of civic education for democratic socialisation both in post-communist states and more generally.Einige Forschungsergebnisse zeigen, dass Staaten, die den Kommunismus durchlaufen haben, eine begrenztere Form von Politikunterricht an Schulen durchfuhren und auf diese Weise Burger heranziehen, die dazu tendieren, den Status Quo zu akzeptieren anstatt politische Entscheidungen kritisch zu hinterfragen und die Politik aktiv mitzugestalten. Die Moglichkeit, jedoch, dass dies auch in einem Staat mit einem ganz anderen geschichtlichen Hintergrund, wie zum Beispiel die Republik Irland, der Fall sein konnte, wird zur Diskussion gestellt. Mit Hilfe von Daten zu politischen Einstellungen aus der European/World Values Survey und der European Social Survey soll diese Frage untersucht werden. Die Ergebnisse unterstutzen zum Teil diese Idee und zeigen, dass Einstellungen in sowohl der fruheren Deutschen Demokratischen Republik als auch in der Republik Irland eher eine Tendenz zu Anpassung aufweisen, was die Wichtigkeit der politischen Bildung für demokratische Sozialization nicht nur in Staaten, die den Kommunismus durchlaufen haben sondern im Allgemeinen betont.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2013-08-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/669</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-669</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 4-2013 Citizenship and Civic Education in Postcommunist Countries</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 4-2013 Citizenship and Civic Education in Postcommunist Countries</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/669/714</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-669</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2013 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>