<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>704</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">The Greek Financial Crisis: Discourses of Difference or Solidarity?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Bickes, Hans</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Otten, Tina</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Weymann, Laura Chelsea</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">The so-called Greek Financial Crisis, which has been the object of close attention in the German media since the end of 2009, has caused a public debate on who should be held responsible for the decline of crisis-hit Greece, the common currency and the Eurozone. The media’s enduring and controversial public discussion has lately been referred to as the Greek bashing. When the crisis had spread much further in 2012 and also other countries suffered from high debt, economic stagnation and unemployment, the news coverage became more moderate. This project report highlights the role of medial discourses of difference and solidarity during the crisis. Therefore, we rely on an exemplary data-set that does not only take the development of the German media’s tenor on the Greek Crisis into consideration, but also adds an international perspective in order to compare the medial treatment of different countries involved. The study methodologically focuses on the analysis of (metaphorical) language and grammatical structures in the news coverage of the German daily newspaper BILD, the German magazine SPIEGEL as well as the international news magazines Economist (Great Britain) and TIME (USA). Therefore, the interdisciplinary approach of Critical Discourse Analysis (CDA) was used in order to produce insights into public discourses in sociopolitical contexts.Deutsche Medien haben der sogenannten Griechischen Finanzkrise erhebliche Aufmerksamkeit gewidmet. Im Hinblick auf die Verantwortlichkeiten für den Niedergang Griechenlands, für die Krise des Euros und der Eurozone war die öffentliche Meinung in Deutschland gespalten. Damit einher ging eine anhaltende und kontroverse mediale Diskussion, die aufgrund des teils rüden Stils alsbald als Greek bashing bezeichnet wurde. Nachdem sich die Krise 2012 auf andere Mitgliedsstaaten ausdehnte und dort zu hoher Staatsverschuldung, ökonomischer Stagnation und Arbeitslosigkeit führte, nahmen Mediendiskurse (auch zu Griechenland) etwas moderatere Züge an. In unserem Projektbericht rekonstruieren wir die Rolle, die Mediendiskurse der Differenz und der Solidarität im Verlauf der Krise gespielt haben. Beispielhaft zeichnen wir diesen Prozess an Daten aus deutschen Medien nach, ergänzen diesen Blickwinkel jedoch durch eine zusätzliche, internationale Perspektive, indem wir die Ergebnisse einer vergleichenden Analyse ausgewählter Medien aus drei Ländern präsentieren. Methodologisch stützen wir uns auf Analysen (metaphorischen) Sprachgebrauchs und grammatischer Strukturen in den Berichterstattungen des deutschen Boulevardblattes BILD sowie der Nachrichtenmagazine SPIEGEL (Deutschland), Economist (Großbritannien) und TIME (USA). Wir bedienen uns des interdisziplinären Ansatzes der Kritischen Diskursanalyse (KDA), um Einsichten in öffentliche Diskurse in soziopolitischen Kontexten zu fördern.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-05-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/704</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-704</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 3-2014 Young Europeans in an Era of Crises: Citizenship Education in a New Perspective</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 3-2014 Young Europeans in an Era of Crises: Citizenship Education in a New Perspective</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/704/760</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-704</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2014 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>