<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>781</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">A Qualitative Study on Learning and Teaching With Learning Paths in a Learning Management System</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>De Smet, Cindy</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Valcke, Martin</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Schellens, Tammy</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>De Wever, Bram</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Vanderlinde, Ruben</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">This article presents the findings of a qualitative study (carried out between 2011 and 2013) about the adoption and implementation of learning paths within a Learning Management System (LMS). Sixteen secondary school biology teachers of the GO! Network in Flanders (an urbanized region in Belgium) were involved in the study and questioned via semi-structured interviews. Two research questions are addressed: (1) what are the perceived conditions at school and at teacher level affecting the use of learning paths? (2) how are these conditions related to the expected outcomes? Research results show teachers are satisfied with learning paths as an educational tool, but reflect mixed feelings as to the impact on student learning outcomes. Clear barriers are identified at the school and teacher level, thwarting the implementation of learning paths in secondary education. The availability of a reliable and accessible ICT infrastructure, the quality of technical and pedagogical support, teacher professional development and the mastery of teacher Information and Communication Technology competencies, among others, were found to be essential.Questo articolo presenta i risultati di uno studio qualitativo sull'adozione e l'attuazione di percorsi di apprendimento all'interno del Learning Management System (LMS). Sedici insegnanti della scuola secondaria sono stati coinvolti nello studio e interrogati tramite interviste semi-strutturate. Si sono prese in considerazione due domande di ricerca: (1) quali sono le condizioni percepite nella scuola e fra gli insegnanti capaci di influenzare l'uso di percorsi di apprendimento (learning paths)? (2) come sono legate ai risultati attesi queste condizioni? I risultati della ricerca mostrano che gli insegnanti sono soddisfatti dei percorsi di apprendimento (learning paths) come strumento educativo, ma mostrano sentimenti contrastanti per quanto riguarda l'impatto sui risultati di apprendimento degli studenti. Si identificano chiari ostacoli a livello di scuola e di insegnanti, vanificando l'utilizzo dei learning paths nell’ istruzione secondaria. Si sono rivelati essenziali, fra l’altro, la disponibilità di infrastruttura ICT affidabili e accessibili, la qualità del supporto tecnico e pedagogico, lo sviluppo professionale degli insegnanti e la padronanza delle tecnologie dell'informazione e della comunicazione.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-03-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/781</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-781</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 1-2016 Digital Tools and Social Science Education; 27-37</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 1-2016 Digital Tools and Social Science Education; 27-37</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/781/850</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-781</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2016 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>