<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/800</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-05-25T11:45:24Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>jsse:FeT</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Unintended Revelations in History Textbooks: The Precarious Authenticity and Historical Continuity of the Slovak Nation</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Sulikova, Jana</dc:creator>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Purpose: This article proposes an analytical framework that helps to identify and challenge misconceptions of ethnocentrism found in pre-tertiary teaching resources for history and the social sciences in numerous countries.Design: Drawing on nationalism studies, the analytical framework employs ideas known under the umbrella terms of primordialism, constructivism and ethno-symbolism. In applying it, the conceptualisation of the Slovak nation, as presented in the history textbooks currently used in lower secondary schools in Slovakia, is examined as a case study.Findings: A conceptually inconsistent picture emerges from the findings, displaying prevailing patterns of primordialism and a degree of ethno-symbolism. Nevertheless, the article concludes that history textbooks lend, on a number of occasions, unintended support to constructivism. Hence, both this inconsistency in theoretical approach, and frequent use of problematic assumptions based on primordialism and ethno-symbolism show that the attempts of textbooks’ authors to demonstrate the authenticity and historical continuity of the Slovak nation remain precarious.Research implications: The analytical framework used in this article is well-suited for multi-country examinations of national narratives in curricula and textbooks of history and the social sciences.Practical implications: Teaching materials and pedagogic approaches drawing on constructivism could enhance critical engagement with ethnocentrism in Slovakia and beyond. </dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2016-10-12</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
      <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/800</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-800</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 3-2016 Controversial Issues in the Political Classroom - Continued; 26-39</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; 3-2016 Controversial Issues in the Political Classroom - Continued; 26-39</dc:source>
      <dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/800/877</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/800/878</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/800/879</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-800</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-800</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-800</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2016 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
