<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>873</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Learning About the European Union in Times of Crisis: Portuguese Textbooks’ Normative Visions of European Citizenship</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Piedade, Filipe</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Ribeiro, Norberto</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Loff, Manuel</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Neves, Tiago</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Menezes, Isabel</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Purpose: To investigate how EU related contents are represented in Portuguese upper secondary school textbooks of History and English as a Foreign Language (EFL).Design/methodology/approach: The study performs a textbook analysis on two History textbooks and three EFL textbooks to explore if and how EU related topics are addressed. The methodological approach was mainly qualitative, based on a content analysis of the textbooks, but also includes some quantitative data (e.g., number of paragraphs) to determine the importance given to European topics in each of the selected school subjects.Findings: EFL textbooks have a residual approach to EU topics that is mainly focused in students’ mobility. History textbooks, while containing a significant amount of information about the EU, present it mainly in a non-confrontational perspective and do not prioritize the development of students’ critical thinking about the EU. Our data also points to a predominance of national level citizenship related content, with European citizenship being briefly and normatively presented to the students.Research limitations/implications: EFL is attended by almost 100% of students in the academic track of secondary education, but History is a curricular subject only available to 25-30% of the students; as such, our findings refer to a specific group.Practical implications: Textbooks should include more information about the actual problems and challenges of the EU to foster the development of students’ critical thinking about the EU.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-08-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/873</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-873</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Bd. 17 Nr. 2 (2018): European Identity and Citizenship in Textbooks and Educational Media; 31-40</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Vol. 17 No. 2 (2018): European Identity and Citizenship in Textbooks and Educational Media; 31-40</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/873/1000</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/873/1001</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-873</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-873</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2018 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>