<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>918</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Character Education for Social Action: A Conceptual Analysis of the #iwill Campaign</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Lamb, Michael</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Taylor-Collins, Emma</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Silverglate, Cameron</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Purpose: This article integrates two distinct discourses to show how an Aristotelian account of character education can supply a valuable framework for developing a habit of social action.
Approach: We use a review of relevant secondary literature, a documentary analysis of #iwill materials, and an Aristotelian conceptual framework to analyse the quality principles of the #iwill campaign—a cross-sector, cross-party collective impact campaign that encourages youth social action in the UK.
Findings: We show how an Aristotelian account offers useful resources for conceptualising andapplying #iwill’s six quality principles and addresses four practical and theoretical challenges in #iwill’s model. In particular, an Aristotelian account provides a more capacious conception of a habit and offers a revised model for understanding social action’s benefits to individuals and communities.
Practical Implications: With over 800 partner organizations in the UK, #iwill has a significant impact on how social action is practised and supplies a valuable model for other campaigns to follow. By informing #iwill’s quality framework, this Aristotelian account seeks to amplify efforts to cultivate social action as a virtuous habit for life.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">sowi-online e.V., Bielefeld, Germany</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-02-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/918</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/jsse-918</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Bd. 18 Nr. 1 (2019): National Holidays and other Socio-Political Rituals in Schools</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education; Vol. 18 No. 1 (2019): National Holidays and other Socio-Political Rituals in Schools</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1618-5293</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.jsse.org/index.php/jsse/article/view/918/1450</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>10.4119/jsse-918</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2019 JSSE - Journal of Social Science Education</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>