<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>5279</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">Bakterien als Plastikmüllabfuhr: Können Mikroorganismen unser globales Plastikproblem lösen?</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Bacteria as waste disposal service:  </dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Chow, Jennifer</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Preuß, Lena</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Gruscke, Marno Falk</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Streit, Wolfgang</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Mikrobieller Plastikabbau</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Plastikmüll</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Enzyme</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Mikroplastik</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Esterasen</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Cutinasen</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">Trotz erster Erfolge beim mikrobiellen PET-Abbau gibt es für die meisten Plastiksorten keine bekannten mikrobiellen Abbauwege. Mikrobieller Abbau von synthetischen Polymeren (Kunststoffen oder Plastik) ist ein wichtiges Forschungsfeld, das sich gerade erst entwickelt. Erste Erfolge zeigen, dass amorphes PET und auf Esterbindungen aufgebautes PUR durch Enzyme (Esterasen und Cutinasen) zumindest unter Laborbedingungen abbaubar sind. Das ist vielversprechend und liefert die Grundlage für erste biotechnologische Re- und Upcycling-Verfahren. Auch gibt es erste Hinweise darauf, dass PET in der Natur durch sezernierte Enzyme über sehr lange Zeiträume abgebaut werden kann. Für die große Mehrzahl (&amp;gt; 85 %) der synthetischen und auf Rohöl basierenden Polymere gibt es jedoch zurzeit keine gesicherten Erkenntnisse über mögliche Abbauwege und daran beteiligte Enzyme. Hier besteht weiterhin sehr großer Forschungsbedarf.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Despite initial successes in microbial PET degradation, there are no known microbial degradation pathways for most types of plastic. Microbial degradation of synthetic polymers (synthetics or plastic) is an important research areathat is just emerging. Initial successes show that amorphous PET and PUR based on ester bonds can be degraded by enzymes (esterases und cutinases), at least under laboratory conditions. This is promising and provides the basis for the first biotechnological recycling and upcycling processes. There are also first indications that PET can be degraded in nature by secreted enzymes over a very long period of time. Notably, for the vast majority (&amp;gt; 85 %) of synthetic and crude oil-based polymers, however, there is still no reliable knowledge of possible degradation pathways and the microbial enzymes involved. Here in particular, there is still a great need for research.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="de-DE">VBIO - Verband Biologie, Biowissenschaften &amp; Biomedizin in Deutschland</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-03-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.biuz.de/index.php/biuz/article/view/5279</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.11576/biuz-5279</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">Biologie in unserer Zeit; Early Views</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Biologie in unserer Zeit; Early Views</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1521-415X</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0045-205X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>deu</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.biuz.de/index.php/biuz/article/view/5279/4876</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">Copyright (c) 2022 Jennifer Chow, Lena Preuß, Marno Falk Gruscke, Wolfgang Streit</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>