<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/2829</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-07-01T11:49:16Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>ijcv:FS8</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Boundaries, Discrimination, and Interethnic Conflict in Xinjiang, China</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Han, Enze</dc:creator>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en-US">The Xinjiang Uighur Autonomous Region has been afflicted by Uighur political activism and ethnic violence for the past few decades. Interethnic&amp;nbsp;relations&amp;nbsp;between the Uighurs and Han Chinese have been extremely tense. Why is Xinjiang so vulnerable to interethnic&amp;nbsp;violence? Why are intergroupdynamics&amp;nbsp;between the Uighurs and Han Chinese so volatile? This paper examines Uighur&amp;ndash;Han Chinese relations in contemporary Xinjiang and probes conditions&amp;nbsp;that facilitate interethnic&amp;nbsp;violence. Utilizing Fredrik Barth&amp;rsquo;s approach to ethnicity that emphasizes boundaries, this paper examines in detail how the rigid&amp;nbsp;interethnic&amp;nbsp;boundary between the Uighurs and Han Chinese has been constructed and strengthened in Xinjiang. Perceived differences have generated&amp;nbsp;mutual distrust and discrimination between the two groups that make intergroup&amp;nbsp;communication and understanding difficult and therefore very limited.&amp;nbsp;In situations such as that in Xinjiang, where a rigid intergroup&amp;nbsp;boundary is in place and civic engagements across groups are lacking, intergroup&amp;nbsp;conflict isextremely hard to avoid.</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Institute for Interdisciplinary Conflict and Violence Research, Bielefeld University</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2010-11-29</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Interview and Observation</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.ijcv.org/index.php/ijcv/article/view/2829</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/ijcv-2829</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">International Journal of Conflict and Violence (IJCV); Bd. 4 Nr. 2 (2010); 244-256</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">International Journal of Conflict and Violence (IJCV); Vol. 4 No. 2 (2010); 244-256</dc:source>
      <dc:source>1864-1385</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.ijcv.org/index.php/ijcv/article/view/2829/pdf_2</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 International Journal of Conflict and Violence</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
