<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>2874</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Governance, Security and Culture: Assessing Africa’s Youth Bulge</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Sommers, Marc</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Although Africa has a youth-dominated population, African government policies are often not youth-centered and African governments and their international supporters are frequently under-informed about the priorities of most youth. Reliance on the “youth bulge and instability thesis” leads to distorted assessments of everyday realities. Examination of the lives, priorities, and cultural contexts of African youth, and the cases of youth in Rwanda and Burundi in particular, shows that the nature of relations between the state and massive populations of young, marginalized, and alienated citizens directly impacts the governance, security, and development prospects of African nations.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Institute for Interdisciplinary Conflict and Violence Research, Bielefeld University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2011-11-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Analysis</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>application/epub+zip</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.ijcv.org/index.php/ijcv/article/view/2874</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/ijcv-2874</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">International Journal of Conflict and Violence (IJCV); Bd. 5 Nr. 2 (2011); 292-303</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">International Journal of Conflict and Violence (IJCV); Vol. 5 No. 2 (2011); 292-303</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1864-1385</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.ijcv.org/index.php/ijcv/article/view/2874/pdf_27</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://www.ijcv.org/index.php/ijcv/article/view/2874/2690</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 International Journal of Conflict and Violence</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>