<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/2912</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-07-01T11:49:14Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>ijcv:F14</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="en-US">From Clinical-Developmental Theory to Assessment: The Holistic Student Assessment Tool</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Noam, Gil</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Malti, Tina</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Guhn, Martin</dc:creator>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en-US">A description and test of the Holistic Student Assessment Tool (HSA), an assessment tool to measure children&amp;rsquo;s and adolescents&amp;rsquo; resiliencies in relation to externalizingand internalizing problem behaviors. The HSA is based on the authors&amp;rsquo; research-based clinical-developmental Clover Leaf Model of resilience and&amp;nbsp;psychopathology, and is one of the first attempts at closing the gap between risk and resilience approaches in developmental assessment. The HSA was tested&amp;nbsp;in a cross-sectional sample of 423 children and adolescents.The results lend support to the HSA as a valid measure of children&amp;rsquo;s and adolescents&amp;rsquo; resiliencies. Furthermore, the resilience scales mostly exhibited the theoreticallyexpected convergent and divergent relationships with the psychopathology scales. In addition, we show how the resilience scales predict adolescents&amp;rsquo;&amp;nbsp;externalizing and internalizing symptoms. We contend that evidence-based intervention to address youth aggression needs to be based on sound&amp;nbsp;developmental assessment.</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Institute for Interdisciplinary Conflict and Violence Research, Bielefeld University</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2012-11-19</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:type xml:lang="en-US">correlational study</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:format>application/epub+zip</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.ijcv.org/index.php/ijcv/article/view/2912</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/ijcv-2912</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">International Journal of Conflict and Violence (IJCV); Bd. 6 Nr. 2 (2012); 201-213</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">International Journal of Conflict and Violence (IJCV); Vol. 6 No. 2 (2012); 201-213</dc:source>
      <dc:source>1864-1385</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.ijcv.org/index.php/ijcv/article/view/2912/pdf_69</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>https://www.ijcv.org/index.php/ijcv/article/view/2912/2767</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 International Journal of Conflict and Violence</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
