<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>2913</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Preventing Child Behavior Problems in the Erlangen-Nuremberg Development and Prevention Study: Results from Preschool to Secondary School Age</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Lösel, Friedrich</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Stemmler, Mark</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">A brief overview of the prevention part of the long-term Erlangen-Nuremberg Development and Prevention Study, which combines a prospective longitudinal&amp;nbsp;and experimental design. Findings up to five years after intervention are reported. From a sample of 609 families with kindergarten children, subgroups participated&amp;nbsp;in the universal prevention program EFFEKT (child social skills training, a parent training and a combination of both) or were assigned to equivalentcontrol groups. The short-term evaluation showed significant effects in mediating constructs (social problem solving and parenting behavior) and in educators&amp;rsquo;&amp;nbsp;ratings of children&amp;rsquo;s social behavior. In a follow-up after two to three years, school report cards showed fewer children with multiple behavior problems. In a&amp;nbsp;further follow up after four to five years program children reported fewer externalizing and internalizing problems than the control group. There were no significant&amp;nbsp;effects in the mothers&amp;rsquo; reports on their children&amp;rsquo;s behavior. Most significant effect sizes ranged between d = 0.20 and d = 0.40. The findings suggest&amp;nbsp;various positive long-term effects of the intervention. However, one need to be cautious with regard to over-generalizing the positive findings, because effect&amp;nbsp;sizes vary over time and the positive findings could not be replicated in all investigated variables.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Institute for Interdisciplinary Conflict and Violence Research, Bielefeld University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2012-11-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">evaluation study</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>application/epub+zip</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://www.ijcv.org/index.php/ijcv/article/view/2913</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.4119/ijcv-2913</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">International Journal of Conflict and Violence (IJCV); Bd. 6 Nr. 2 (2012); 214-224</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">International Journal of Conflict and Violence (IJCV); Vol. 6 No. 2 (2012); 214-224</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1864-1385</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://www.ijcv.org/index.php/ijcv/article/view/2913/pdf_70</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://www.ijcv.org/index.php/ijcv/article/view/2913/2769</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 International Journal of Conflict and Violence</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>