<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Record>
  <header status="">
    <identifier>oai:biejournals.de:article/2943</identifier>
    <datestamp>2020-07-01T11:49:13Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>ijcv:ED</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Editorial: Letter from the Editors</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Heitmeyer, Wilhelm</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Massey, Douglas S.</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Messner, Steven F.</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Sidanius, James</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Wieviorka, Michel</dc:creator>
      <dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Dear Reader,This issue of the journal features a double focus for the first time. Opening with insights into processes of transitional justice (guest editors Susanne Buckley-Zistel and Thorsten Bonacker), it moves on to a variety of explorations in the field of prejudice using qualitative method approaches (guest edited by Felix Knappertsbusch, Björn Milbradt, and Udo Kelle). Our sincere thanks to both guest editing teams for the interesting and worthwhile focus sections they haveassembled.The two papers in the open section once again reflect the diversity of the field of conflict and violence: terrorist internet forums are the topic of the first article,while the second examines the classical sociological topic of youth violence.The next issue, to appear in autumn 2013, will focus on intimate partner violence. Until then we invite you to visit our new early view section every once in a while to check on pre-releases.June 2013Wilhelm HeitmeyerDouglas S. MasseySteven F. MessnerJames SidaniusMichel Wieviorka</dc:description>
      <dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Institute for Interdisciplinary Conflict and Violence Research, Bielefeld University</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2013-06-17</dc:date>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
      <dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dc:format>application/epub+zip</dc:format>
      <dc:identifier>https://www.ijcv.org/index.php/ijcv/article/view/2943</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier>10.4119/ijcv-2943</dc:identifier>
      <dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">International Journal of Conflict and Violence (IJCV); Bd. 7 Nr. 1 (2013); 3</dc:source>
      <dc:source xml:lang="en-US">International Journal of Conflict and Violence (IJCV); Vol. 7 No. 1 (2013); 3</dc:source>
      <dc:source>1864-1385</dc:source>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:relation>https://www.ijcv.org/index.php/ijcv/article/view/2943/pdf_112</dc:relation>
      <dc:relation>https://www.ijcv.org/index.php/ijcv/article/view/2943/2830</dc:relation>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 International Journal of Conflict and Violence</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/4.0</dc:rights>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
  <about/>
</Record>
